<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Golden Tips - Newspaper Coverage</title>
  <updated>2025-02-14T02:54:41-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Golden Tips</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/bt-picks-golden-tips-valentines-special-tea-combo-a-complete-review</id>
    <published>2025-02-14T02:54:41-06:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-14T03:00:05-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/bt-picks-golden-tips-valentines-special-tea-combo-a-complete-review"/>
    <title>BT Picks: Golden Tips Valentine&apos;s Special Tea Combo – A Complete Review</title>
    <author>
      <name>Marketing Golden Tips Teas</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 16px;">Golden Tips is one of India’s oldest and most reputed tea brands, known for sourcing high-quality teas from Darjeeling. Their Valentine’s Special Combo features three floral-infused tea blends—Hibiscus Rose Black Tea, Rose Green Tea, and Rose Black Tea - crafted for a fragrant and flavourful experience. Here's the full review.</span></p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/bt-picks-golden-tips-valentines-special-tea-combo-a-complete-review">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[
<p style="font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600; font-style: italic; margin: 24px 0; line-height: 38px;">First published on <a class="text-link" href="https://www.bombaytimes.com/bt-picks/bt-picks-golden-tips-valentine-s-special-tea-combo-a-complete-review/1739351928824" target="_blank">Bombay Times</a></p>
<img class="w-100" style="display: block; margin: 20px 0 10px 0;" alt="World Best Teas" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Bombaytimes-1.png?v=1739517482">
<p style="text-align: justify;">Golden Tips is one of India’s oldest and most reputed tea brands, known for sourcing high-quality teas from Darjeeling. Their Valentine’s Special Combo features three floral-infused tea blends—Hibiscus Rose Black Tea, Rose Green Tea, and Rose Black Tea - crafted for a fragrant and flavourful experience. Here's the full review.</p>
<h2 class="mt-5"><strong>Why This Product?</strong></h2>
<img class="w-100" style="display: block; margin: 20px 0 10px 0;" alt="World Best Teas" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Bombaytimes-2.png?v=1739517482">
<p class="custom-text-1 mb-1">This special edition set brings together floral and earthy notes. The Hibiscus Rose Black Tea has a tart, slightly citrusy taste, while the Rose Green Tea is light, refreshing, and subtly sweet. The Rose Black Tea balances robustness with delicate floral undertones, making it a well-rounded option for tea lovers.</p>
<h2 class="mt-5"><strong>Packaging</strong></h2>
<img class="w-100" style="display: block; margin: 20px 0 10px 0;" alt="World Best Teas" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Bombaytimes-3.png?v=1739517483">
<p style="text-align: justify;">The teas come in elegant tin boxes, making them a visually appealing gift option. The packaging preserves freshness while adding a premium touch. Ideal for gifting on Valentine's Day or as a treat for tea connoisseurs.</p>
<h2 class="mt-5"><strong>Usage</strong></h2>
<img class="w-100" style="display: block; margin: 20px 0 10px 0;" alt="World Best Teas" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Bombaytimes-4.png?v=1739517482"><p style="text-align: justify;">To get the most out of these floral teas, add 2 gm tea leaves in a pot. Pour 200 ml freshly boiled water over leaves. Cover the pot and steep for 2-3 minutes. Strain and serve. Adding honey or lemon can enhance the natural floral notes, but the teas taste great on their own as well. For an iced tea version, steep the leaves, let the tea cool, and serve over ice for a refreshing drink. These teas are best enjoyed without milk to preserve their delicate flavours.</p>
<h2 class="mt-5"><strong>Cost</strong></h2>
<img class="w-100" style="display: block; margin: 20px 0 10px 0;" alt="World Best Teas" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Bombaytimes-5.png?v=1739517483">
<p style="text-align: justify;">Priced at ₹965, the Valentine’s Special Combo sits in the premium tea category. While it may seem expensive, the quality of whole-leaf tea, floral infusions, and elegant packaging justify the cost. It’s an indulgence, but for those who appreciate high-quality, naturally flavoured teas, it could be a worthwhile purchase.</p>
<h2 class="mt-5"><strong>What We Love</strong></h2>
<img class="w-100" style="display: block; margin: 20px 0 10px 0;" alt="World Best Teas" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Bombaytimes-6.png?v=1739517483">
<p style="text-align: justify;">These teas offer a rich floral aroma and a versatile brewing experience, perfect for both hot and iced preparations. Packed with antioxidants and health benefits, they aid digestion and reduce stress. The premium tin packaging enhances freshness, making it an ideal gift or a luxurious addition to any tea collection. </p> 
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/golden-tips-a-tea-brand-with-a-strong-social-ethos</id>
    <published>2024-08-02T03:18:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:18:45-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/golden-tips-a-tea-brand-with-a-strong-social-ethos"/>
    <title>Golden Tips: A Tea Brand with a strong Social ethos</title>
    <author>
      <name>Marketing Golden Tips Teas</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span data-mce-fragment="1">Darjeeling, the queen of hills is famous for its idyllic landscapes and lush green tea gardens. Golden Tips, a premium home-grown tea brand from the region has taken several social and humanitarian initiatives in Darjeeling over the years.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/golden-tips-a-tea-brand-with-a-strong-social-ethos">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="full-article-details">
<p>Darjeeling, the queen of hills is famous for its idyllic landscapes and lush green tea gardens. Golden Tips, a premium home-grown tea brand from the region has taken several social and humanitarian initiatives in Darjeeling over the years. With a heritage of over 8 decades and roots firmly planted in the Darjeeling region, the brand has always tried to make lives of this vibrant hill stations inhabitants better.</p>
<div class="approved_content p-0 tabcontent show clearfix previewarticlecontent" id="tab1">
<div class="article-content-section">
<p><span> Darjeeling, the queen of hills is famous for its idyllic landscapes and lush green tea gardens. </span><span>Golden Tips, a premium home-grown tea brand from the region has taken several social and humanitarian initiatives in Darjeeling over the years. With a heritage of over 8 decades and roots firmly planted in the Darjeeling region, the brand has always tried to make lives of this vibrant hill stations inhabitants better. </span></p>
<p><span>During the pandemic, the company earnestly came forward and did its bit by distributing free foodgrains and medical aid to the poor and needy who were the worst hit owing to the global epidemic.</span></p>
<img style="display: block; margin: 20px 0 10px 0;" src="https://press-release-v1.s3.ap-south-1.amazonaws.com/order/8294/1719827653096_0.png" alt="" width="602" height="401">
<p>Madhav Sarda , Managing Director Golden Tips teas</p>
From time to time, Golden Tips has served exotic Darjeeling teas and snacks in several marathons, sports events like tennis tournaments etc., seminars, special occasions like International Tea Day, Independence Day etc. and many events of Chief Minister, West Bengal Mamata Banerjee. In fact, Ms. Banerjee visited the brand’s tea boutique located in the main promenade of the town - Chowrasta with her entourage and media persons recently. She thoroughly enjoyed the teas and savouries offered to her and also appreciated the picturesque surroundings, aesthetics of the tea boutique and hospitality given by Golden Tips staff. Hitherto, Ex President of India, Late Sh. Pranab Mukherjee also visited Golden Tips tea stores in Darjeeling during his tenure as the President of India and enjoyed his visit.
<p><span>Mr Piyush Goel, Union Commerce and Industry Minister had also visited Golden Tips tea boutique sometime back and spent considerable amount of time enjoying the locales, delicious teas and interacting with the brand’s staff. </span></p>
<p><span>Recently, international T20 delegates visited the tea boutiques of Golden Tips in Darjeeling and had a gala time there. Complimentary teas, delectable snacks were offered to the distinguished dignitaries. They were also presented with premium luxury tea in specially designed gift boxes. </span></p>
<p><span>Top Celebrities, Film actors, Music Directors and Singers from Bollywood, Tollywood, Kollywood and other regional film industries have also thronged the numerous tea boutiques and office premises of the brand. Some International Film Directors have also shot their films in the picturesque outdoor locales of office premises overseeing the majestic Kanchenjunga and verdant Darjeeling hills. </span></p>
<h3><strong>About of GOLDEN TIPS TEA</strong></h3>
<p>The expertise of GOLDEN TIPS lies in sourcing, sampling, choosing, packaging and marketing of the finest single origin teas, tea blends and infusions. The company operates primarily through its in-house retail outlets (14+ stores mainly in Darjeeling, Mirik, Kalimpong, Gangtok, Bagdogra and Kolkata<span>), Omni - Channel route, through leading retail stores at select cities and airports in the country and from the company’s website <u>www.goldentipstea.</u></span><u>com</u> apart from online marketplaces like Amazon, Flipkart, etc. The company has shipped its premium teas to almost 90 countries in the last several years through its website &amp; online channels. GOLDEN TIPS also has exclusive representations in Russia, Japan, Mongolia, Nepal, Bhutan and now China.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/my-cup-of-joy</id>
    <published>2024-08-02T03:16:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:16:55-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/my-cup-of-joy"/>
    <title>My Cup Of Joy</title>
    <author>
      <name>Marketing Golden Tips Teas</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div data-mce-fragment="1">
<div data-mce-fragment="1"><span>As the son the Late Nandlall Sarda and the grandson of the Late Nathmull Sarda, who founded the tea business in Darjeeling back in 1933, my initiation into the world of teas happened very early in life.</span></div>
</div><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/my-cup-of-joy">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600; font-style: italic; margin: 24px 0; line-height: 38px;">First published on <a class="text-link" href="https://www.marwar.com/archive/my-cup-of-joy/"> Marwar</a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As the son the Late Nandlall Sarda and the grandson of the Late Nathmull Sarda, who founded the tea business in Darjeeling back in 1933, my initiation into the world of teas happened very early in life. Our family originally hails from Taranagar, Churu District, Rajasthan, and moved sometime early in the 20th Century. My family, especially my parents, have had a profound impact on my personality since my childhood. My value system, sense of heritage and my business acumen have been passed on to me by my ancestors. I was born and raised in Darjeeling, West Bengal, where I did my schooling from St Joseph’s School followed by graduation from St Joseph’s College. The tranquil environs of Kanchenjunga, amidst the idyllic and scenic surroundings of the Himalayas and the tea plantations of Darjeeling had a lasting impact on my life. I joined my family business at a fairly young age when I was still in college. The initial days were challenging yet interesting and with a lot of learnings along the way. The opportunity to meet and interact with tourists from India and across the world became an integral part of my learning experience. I currently live in Delhi, but keep visiting Darjeeling for work.</p>
<hr>
<h3>On The Tea Trail</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It was in 1989 that Golden Tips Tea got established and in 1993 the brand got formally launched at select stores in the country. In the initial years, there were about 35 offerings of the finest Indian teas. The company now offers 300+ varieties of tea in different packaging and styles. These teas are primarily from Darjeeling, but a few others originate from Assam, Sikkim, the Nilgiris, Kangra and even Japan. Our expertise lies in sourcing, sampling, choosing, packaging and marketing the finest single origin teas, tea blends and infusions, at the right prices, for a crosssection of tea drinkers. The practice of sourcing tea directly from the producers ensures optimum realisation for farmers and better living conditions for workers. As the Managing Director of Golden Tips Tea, I have an all-encompassing role in managing the affairs of the company. This involves conceptualising and initiating new retail stores, appointing and training key personnel to run various verticals of the company including exports, product development, designing and packaging, online sales, sourcing, tasting, and selecting the finest teas for our global clients. My wife Ranjeeta Sarda is the Director of Golden Tips while my son Bala Sarda and daughter Nupur Sarda head another tea brand Vahdam Teas.</p>
<hr>
<h3>It’s Always Tea O’ Clock</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I drink tea with great pleasure. A typical day for me begins around 7 am with four newspapers and a big pot of Darjeeling tea, without any hint of milk or sugar in it. I enjoy 4-5 cups of tea over an hour and a half, and while the first cup is quite hot, the second one gets warm and by the time I have my last cup, the tea is cool, yet as refreshing as the first one. Within 10 minutes of reaching the office, I am handed another cup of tea and this continues until I am home for dinner. On an average, I have about 10-12 cups of tea ranging from ones being packed for sale to new samples. I have milk tea or coffee, to which I do add sugar, once a week or fortnightly. It’s mostly on Sundays, when I am home, that I may tell my wife, ‘Let’s have doodh ki chai’. Having tea and tasting tea are two different concepts. When I am tasting tea, I don’t take a drop right down my throat, I just slurp and roll the tea in my mouth and then spit it out. Almost like wine tasting, but more intense, as I taste almost 30-35 teas in one session, depending upon the size of the table.</p>
<hr>
<h3>Makings Of A Tea Taster</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There are two methods of becoming a tea taster: the first, when a person belongs to a tea family or background, and the second, when the person comes from a non-tea background. It is important for a ‘new person’ to first join the industry, which means joining an auction house. We have 4-5 big tea auction houses in India, the biggest being J Thomas &amp; Company, which has been here since pre- Independence with offices in Kolkata, Siliguri, Guwahati and Kochi. These auction houses have a panel of tea tasters, who taste samples that are put up every week or are routed privately to them by tea estates and companies. The new person has to undergo a formal training under these qualified and experienced tea tasters How did I become a tea taster? The journey started completely differently as I belong to a family that has been in the tea business for decades. I first started tasting teas in our retail store in Darjeeling when I was 18. These would be tea samples from tea estates, or the teas we would buy directly from tea plantations in Darjeeling or from accredited buyers from auction houses, as we were not accredited buyers at the time. I didn’t have much guidance, as I lost my father when I was just 10 years old. So, I am pretty much self-taught.</p>
<hr>
<h3>The Tea Journey</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Once I had a better understanding of teas, I opened a small office in Kolkata (then Calcutta). Even though I had started living in Delhi, I would travel to Kolkata and spend several days there. We had a small team back then but we weren’t members of the Calcutta Tea Traders Association (CTTA) yet, so we had to buy teas from an agent. I remember visiting auction houses, meeting tea tasters and tasting teas at their offices. I often brought back samples to my office and my residence in Kolkata, where I would prepare the teas myself, set up the tasting bowls and taste the teas. Once we became members of CTTA in 1989, we started receiving samples, which later turned into hundreds of free samples. I started tasting tea in Kolkata, and later they were packed and sent to me in Delhi a week before the auctions. So, I started tasting them in my Delhi residence as well. The ambit of my tasting increased exponentially. This is when I started bidding and buying, observing and understanding the type of tea being sold and their prices. Although it has been almost four decades now, I still continue to taste tea. It doesn’t matter if I buy them or not, but I need to taste tea! It is the beginning of the new season and I have been flooded with samples from tea estates. I also receive samples from Guwahati and the Nilgiris, and all of these teas are so unique in character, flavour, liquor and appearance. We do tea tasting in our Tea Boutique, where I get to meet a lot of curious customers and tourists. Many of them come up to me and say how excited they are to finally meet an expert tea taster and ask various questions about the process.</p>
<p><img sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.marwar.com/archive/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Sipping-his-way-to-glory.jpg 1024w, https://www.marwar.com/archive/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Sipping-his-way-to-glory-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.marwar.com/archive/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Sipping-his-way-to-glory-768x512.jpg 768w" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28328" height="683" width="1024" alt="" src="http://www.marwar.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Sipping-his-way-to-glory.jpg" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Sipping His Way To Glory</p>
<hr>
<h3>A Holistic Experience</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Tea tasting is primarily about experience, learning, understanding the teas and using your sense of smell. It always helps if there’s someone to guide you through this process. During tea tasting, all your senses have to work in unison, or you won’t do justice to the art of tasting. You need to notice the smallest of details —the appearance of the dry leaf, of the infused leaf, the colour of the liquor, the smell and the taste. The more you taste, the better you become. There is no shortcut to becoming an expert tea taster. Passion is equally important. Of course, you need the caliber and talent too. Your passion for teas and tea tasting will reflect on the popularity of your brand. Brands that do well have great insights into picking the right teas at the right price. Memory also plays an important role in tea tasting. I might have tasted a particular tea two decades back, but the taste and aroma are still a part of my memory! Let me explain how memory shapes our tea drinking experience. I remember meeting a gentleman a few years back in our Darjeeling Tea Boutique. He wanted to have the same tea he had tried 25 years ago, when he had visited our estate along with his newly-wed wife. I had to politely tell him that he would never be able to replicate the experience of being a newlywed, sipping aromatic Darjeeling tea in a picturesque tea garden, overlooking the majestic Mt. Kanchenjunga.</p>
<hr>
<h3>The Fascination of Tea Tasting</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">How amazing it is to be able to sip, smell and swirl a wide range of teas from different regions and seasons, cultivars and clones, with varied characteristics like appearance, texture, colour, aroma and flavour. My gustatory olfactory senses run on overdrive when I am surrounded by a wide array of teas with floral, vegetal, fruity, smoky, muscatel, malty or astringent characteristics. I only taste Orthodox Tea, which is the traditional, long leaf tea variety. I am not an expert in the art of tasting CTC, also known as Crush, Tear and Curl. These are granular teas, mostly produced in Assam, the Dooars and in southern parts of India.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Darjeeling does not produce CTC. I have seen people add milk to CTC, and it is not for the taste, but to check how the colour behaves. CTC tasters often leave the mixture for 2-3 hours to check how the colour of the brew changes.</p>
<p><img sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.marwar.com/archive/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Madhav-Sardha-on-a-tea-trail.jpg 1024w, https://www.marwar.com/archive/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Madhav-Sardha-on-a-tea-trail-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.marwar.com/archive/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Madhav-Sardha-on-a-tea-trail-768x512.jpg 768w" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28329" height="683" width="1024" alt="" src="http://www.marwar.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Madhav-Sardha-on-a-tea-trail.jpg" decoding="async"></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Madhav Sardha on a Tea Trail</p>
<hr>
<h3>Our Future Plans</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">At Golden Tips, we plan to add to our existing 14+ tea boutiques in Darjeeling, Kalimpong, Mirik, Gangtok and Kolkata. We are planning to open a one-of-a-kind experience centre in Kolkata, where we will host tea tasting sessions and different events. The domestic market apart, Golden Tips has dedicated customers across the globe and we have shipped teas to almost 90 countries. I am passing on the knowledge of tea tasting to some junior colleagues, and am happy to see their enthusiasm. I am also trying to instil these values in my son Bala Sarda, who is also in the business of tea. I personally believe that we need to pass on this legacy.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/missing-link-in-the-great-indian-tea-bazaar</id>
    <published>2022-09-06T06:25:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:04:26-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/missing-link-in-the-great-indian-tea-bazaar"/>
    <title>Missing link in the great Indian tea bazaar</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Tea planters in picturesque Darjeeling say the biggest challenge for India tea lies in its packaging, because producers rarely package their products.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/missing-link-in-the-great-indian-tea-bazaar">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center">
<div class="col-md-2 "><a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/commodities/missing-link-in-the-great-indian-tea-bazaar-8704161.html" class="fancyboximg"><img class="img-fluid" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/money-control.png?v=1662371648" width=""></a></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/commodities/missing-link-in-the-great-indian-tea-bazaar-8704161.html" class="text-link">Money Control</a><span class="text-link"> </span>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 mt-5">Tea planters in picturesque Darjeeling say the biggest challenge for India tea lies in its packaging, because producers rarely package their products.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">As a result, Indian planters rarely have control over the end product. If that is sorted out, Indian tea can create the perfect storm in the world market.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">There is a big divide among Indian teas sold across the country and shipped abroad. As a result, the world’s second-largest producer does not have the largest slice of the global pie. It is currently ranked fourth. Kenya leads the pack with 28 percent export of its produce, followed by China, the world’s largest producer (19 percent), then Sri Lanka (14 percent) and India (11 percent).</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">What planters say in hushed tones is that Indian tea diplomacy has not achieved the desired results . The Kolkata-based Tea Board has not been able to push the Commerce Ministry to hold nation-to-nation talks to market Indian tea.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Planters across India are doing things mostly on their own, trying to keep up supplies for the domestic market, as well as international markets.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">“Indian planters do not have the necessary cash to pack their own produce. Very few do. This needs to change, with some financial push from the government,” says Rudra Chatterjee, the big boss of Luxmi Tea, which — some years ago — bought out the iconic Makaibari Tea Estate in Kurseong.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Chatterjee is proud of the product he grows. He reminds me that Indian tea is no pushover; it’s a product that occupies centrestage in Indian culture and is produced by an estimated 1,600 tea gardens across India that employ a total workforce of a little over 1.1 million people.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">In short, tea is not just a widely loved beverage, it is a state of mind for millions of Indians.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Calls for change</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Chatterjee said things must start working for planters because the issue of packaging is often discussed at various forums. At a recent meeting in the Indian Capital, planters asked Commerce Minister Piyush Goyal if the government could help the planters do their own packaging by infusing cash. Goyal replied in the affirmative, but also directed the tea growers to look at the meteoric rise of the coffee industry and how coffee growers had a Rs 5,000 crore export tag as compared to the tea growers’ Rs 4,000 crore export tag.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">India produced 1,145 million kg of tea in financial year 2021 (FY2021) but consumed 89 percent of the produce domestically. The rest was exported to Russia, Iran, UAE, the US and China. Indian tea exports in FY21 were worth $704.36 million (Rs 5,311.53 crore).</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">“And remember, we are not even the second-largest exporter. We are way down the ladder. All this needs a serious overhaul,” says Chatterjee, who has plantations in Africa as well.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">“We need to change, we need to adapt modern techniques and do a lot more. People are drinking tea like never before. Planters need quick cash and more cash, they need efficient supply chains and they need modern technology to push their products across the world,” Chatterjee told Moneycontrol.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">At Makaibari, Chatterjee does his own packaging but there are not too many like him in Darjeeling, or in Assam or the Nilgiris. And this is not good news because the Assam, Darjeeling and Nilgiri teas are considered to be among the finest in the world for their strong flavours and intense aromas.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Why maintaining standards is an imperative</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Madhav Sarda, a top tea trader with operations across India and abroad, says India tea should have been given a place of pride long ago and the government should have played an important role to push a product as integral to India as tea, first introduced to the slopes of the Assam hills by British planters way back in 1830s.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">“India tea is too, too scattered across the world. We do not know who is packing what, whether someone is pushing their own variety of tea along with Darjeeling, or whether someone is checking standards. And this is one product so close to our hearts,” Sarda, managing director, Golden Tips, said in an interview in Darjeeling.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Checking and maintaining standards is a big issue with some of the big tea gardens in India.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">A month ago, international and domestic buyers rejected a series of tea consignments due to the presence of pesticides and chemicals beyond permissible limits.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Indian Tea Exporters Association (ITEA) chairman Anshuman Kanoria told Moneycontrol the matter was serious. It is reliably learnt that a large number of consignments from tea gardens in Assam had failed the test.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Kanoria said that post Covid, many nations have put in place very stringent conditions for tea. Many nations follow EU standards, which are more stringent than the FSSAI rules. “India should not send any wrong signals. Tea is not just an ordinary drink; it is considered a health beverage,” Kanoria added.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">India exports its crush-tear-curl (CTC) grade mainly to Egypt and Britain, with the orthodox variety going to Iraq, Iran and Russia.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Chatterjee says it is high time all tea gardens — like Darjeeling — turn organic.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Big changes in the market</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Back to business, Sarda says the tea business in India is undergoing a sea change. Branding and packaging are becoming increasingly important, along with online sales. “Loose tea is not being preferred anymore post Covid; people want packed tea because they consider it safer to drink.”</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">As a result, bulk tea sales, which once dominated the market, are now shrinking. For the record, almost 40 percent of Assam tea in the CTC dust category remained unsold in the Guwahati, Siliguri and Kolkata auction centres during the April-June period this year.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Throughout last year, the figure hovered around 28 percent. And packaged tea sales are growing. The packaged tea market is worth around Rs 24,000 crore, which is half of the 1.3 billion kg tea market in India.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">And then there is a serious demand-supply mismatch, say planters in Darjeeling and Siliguri. Prices were Rs 188-190 per kilo in the Assam CTC and dust categories but are now hovering around Rs 168 per kilo, impacted by heavy rains in Assam this year and high coal prices. Assam, which accounts for over half of India’s production, also suffered because of labour movement restrictions to contain the coronavirus outbreak.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">In comparison, Darjeeling teas, which fall in the estate-specific, single-origin category, were on a high. There was tourism to back the tea markets. “The crowds are mindboggling, our shops are full of customers. The influx of tourists has been huge after two long years,” says Sarda.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">There’s more. Tea, blended with herbs and spices, works as an immunity booster. This, claim planters, is a rage with the new generation, which has already labelled tea as the best option in the $1.5 trillion wellness segment.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Planters in Darjeeling are lobbying hard to bring fusion tea under the Ministry of Ayush. If that happens, Darjeeling tea, which has a sizeable section of fusion tea, could get a slice of the Rs 3,000 crore-plus Ayush marketing budget. Wellness is big news in India, which has a 13.1 percent share of the global market, per a McKinsey study.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">The Indian Tea Association (ITA) is also doing its bit to push tea, with the main focus revolving around increasing consumption across India, including pushing the beverage in Southern Indian states, where coffee rules the roost. Almost all tea gardens are being encouraged by the ITA to open up their bungalows for tourism. Tea planters and traders are being encouraged to push tea among the 20-25 age group through tea lounges. “The idea is to improve the value chain of tea,” says ITA head Nayantara Pal Choudhury, adding: “The goal is to push India to have the largest share of the global tea market by providing quality products.”</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">The Tea Board, which works directly under the Commerce Ministry, is also encouraging small planters to connect with high-end buyers in Australia and South America. “The direct link to the consumer is very important,” said a small planter in Darjeeling. “There is high demand for herbal and organic tea.”</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">An opportunity amid the Lanka void</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">There is one more region where Indian tea could make a market: the global markets of Sri Lankan tea. The mounting economic woes in Sri Lanka — a major player in the global tea market — could open up opportunities for Indian exporters.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Market experts claim that there could be a significant decline in production and shipments of tea from Sri Lanka, which produces around 300 million kg of tea annually, predominantly orthodox tea. Colombo exports 97-98 per cent of its annual output and accounts for almost 50 per cent of the total global trade in orthodox tea. It exports to Iraq, Iran, the UAE, and North African destinations such as Libya, along with Russia and Turkey.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Indian exporters can easily fill the void caused by the fall in Sri Lanka's tea production.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/pomegranate-tea-martini-recipe</id>
    <published>2022-09-05T06:47:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:04:19-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/pomegranate-tea-martini-recipe"/>
    <title>Pomegranate Tea Martini Recipe</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[A refreshing concoction made of fresh pomegranate juice, ginger juliennes and green tea. It is a perfect beverage to sip on during evenings.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/pomegranate-tea-martini-recipe">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center mt-4">
<div class="col-md-2 "><a href="https://food.ndtv.com/recipe-pomegranate-martini-957372" class="fancyboximg"><img class="img-fluid" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/ndtv-food.png?v=1662373226" width=""></a></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="https://food.ndtv.com/recipe-pomegranate-martini-957372" class="text-link">NDTV FOOD</a><span class="text-link"> </span>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">A refreshing concoction made of fresh pomegranate juice, ginger juliennes and green tea. It is a perfect beverage to sip on during evenings.</p>
<div>
<ul>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">
<div class="custom-text mb-10">
<span>Total Cook Time</span><span> 10 mins </span>
</div>
</li>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">
<div class="custom-text mb-10">
<span>Prep Time</span><span> 05 mins </span>
</div>
</li>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">
<div class="custom-text mb-10">
<span>Cook Time</span><span> 05 mins </span>
</div>
</li>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">
<div class="custom-text mb-10">
<span>Recipe Servings 1</span>
</div>
</li>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">
<div class="custom-text mb-10"><span>Easy</span></div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Ingredients of Pomegranate Tea Martini</h2>
<ul>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">2 tbsp Fresh pomegranate seeds</li>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">3-4 Ginger juliennes</li>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">120-130 ml Green Tea</li>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">60 ml Pomegranate juice</li>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">Crushed ice cubes</li>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">10-15 ml Lemon juice</li>
<li class="custom-text mb-10">1 twig Tulsi (for garnishing)</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">How to Make Pomegranate Tea Martini</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">As a result, Indian planters rarely have control over the end product. If that is sorted out, Indian tea can create the perfect storm in the world market.</p>
<div class="custom-text mb-10">
<span>1.</span>Brew the <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/green-teas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">green tea</a> and let it cool down for 30 mins.</div>
<div class="custom-text mb-10">
<span>2.</span>In a cocktail shaker, mix the lemon juice, ginger and pomegranate seeds.</div>
<div class="custom-text mb-10">
<span>3.</span>Add crushed ice cubes, green tea and pomegranate juice.</div>
<div class="custom-text mb-10">
<span>4.</span>Shake rigorously and strain the concoction into a Martini glass.</div>
<div class="custom-text mb-10">
<span>5.</span>Tip: Garnish the mocktail with tulsi leaves for that extra punch of flavour.</div>
<p class="aut_crd-txt"><span class="aut_crd-nm">Key Ingredients: </span>Ginger juliennes, Green Tea, Pomegranate juice, Crushed ice cubes, Lemon juice, Tulsi (for garnishing)</p>
<!--Recipe Schema-->
<script type="application/ld+json">// <![CDATA[
{
	"@context": "http://schema.org/",
	"@type": "Recipe",
	"name": "Pomegranate Tea Martini Recipe",
	"image": [
		"https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/articles/Pomegranate-Tea-Martini-blog_2048x2048.png?v=1662378442"
	],
	"recipeCategory": "Beverages",
	"prepTime": "PT5M",
	"cookTime": "PT5M",
	"totalTime": "PT10M",
	"recipeYield": "1",
	"description": "A refreshing concoction made of fresh pomegranate juice, ginger juliennes and green tea. It is a perfect beverage to sip on during evenings.",
	"keywords": "pomegranate,Martini,martini recipe",
	"author": {
		"@type": "Organization",
		"name": "Golden Tips Tea"
	},
	"nutrition": {
		"@type": "NutritionInformation"
	},
	"recipeIngredient": [
		"2 tbsp Fresh pomegranate seeds",
		"3-4 Ginger juliennes",
		"120-130 ml Green Tea",
		"60 ml Pomegranate juice",
		"Crushed ice cubes",
		"10-15 ml Lemon juice",
		"1 twig Tulsi (for garnishing)"
	],
	"recipeInstructions": [
		{
			"@type": "HowToStep",
			"name": "Brew the green tea",
			"text": "Brew the green tea and let it cool down for 30 mins."
		},
		{
			"@type": "HowToStep",
			"name": "cocktail shaker",
			"text": "In a cocktail shaker, mix the lemon juice, ginger and pomegranate seeds."
		},
		{
			"@type": "HowToStep",
			"name": " crushed ice cubes",
			"text": "Add crushed ice cubes, green tea and pomegranate juice."
		},
		{
			"@type": "HowToStep",
			"name": "Shake and Strain",
			"text": "Shake rigorously and strain the concoction into a Martini glass."
		},
		{
			"@type": "HowToStep",
			"name": "Tip",
			"text": "Tip: Garnish the mocktail with tulsi leaves for that extra punch of flavour."
		}
	]
}
// ]]]]><![CDATA[></script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/tea-retailer-golden-tips-plans-to-expand-network-through-strategic-partnerships</id>
    <published>2022-09-05T02:53:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:05:34-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/tea-retailer-golden-tips-plans-to-expand-network-through-strategic-partnerships"/>
    <title>Tea retailer Golden Tips plans to expand network through strategic partnerships</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Meanwhile, the retailer had purchased organic white tea, a special variety of the beverage, at Rs 23,000 per kilogram and 'Moonlight' tea at Rs 21,000 per kilogram from Goodricke's Badamtam estate in Darjeeling, he said, adding that the prices are the "season's highest so far".<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/tea-retailer-golden-tips-plans-to-expand-network-through-strategic-partnerships">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2 mt-5">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center mt-5">
<div class="col-md-2 "><a target="_blank" href="https://retail.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/food-entertainment/personal-care-pet-supplies-liquor/tea-retailer-golden-tips-plans-to-expand-network-through-strategic-partnerships/90729941" class="fancyboximg" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img class="img-fluid" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/et-retail.png?v=1662362642" width=""></a></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="https://retail.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/food-entertainment/personal-care-pet-supplies-liquor/tea-retailer-golden-tips-plans-to-expand-network-through-strategic-partnerships/90729941" class="text-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">India Times</a><span class="text-link"> </span>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<!-- <h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Can you actually combine the techniques of a mocktail and the flavours of tea?</h2> -->
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Tea retailer Golden Tips plans to expand its footprint through the e-commerce route by entering into strategic partnerships in the country and widen its reach in export markets through distributor tie-ups overseas, an official said on Friday. The company is also focusing on broadening its presence in physical retail operations across metros of the country by opening niche <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/pages/showrooms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tea boutiques</a> and stores, he said.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Darjeeling-based Golden Tips Managing Director Madhav Sarda said the firm is exploring commissioning a few outlets once the COVID-19 pandemic subsides.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Meanwhile, the retailer had purchased <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/white" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">organic white tea</a>, a special variety of the beverage, at Rs 23,000 per kilogram and 'Moonlight' tea at Rs 21,000 per kilogram from Goodricke's Badamtam estate in <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/darjeeling" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Darjeeling</a>, he said, adding that the prices are the "season's highest so far".</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">These <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/first-spring" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spring flush tea</a> varieties would be sold through its retail outlets, Sarda said.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">The company follows the practice of sourcing tea directly from producers as this will ensure that "farmers get optimum realisation and workers get better living conditions", he said.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">This will also insulate them from the volatility of auctions, Sarda said.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">The company now operates 14 retail stores, mostly in eastern India, and sells tea through its website, the official said.</p>
<a href="/blogs/all/procured-top-5-teas-fetching-the-highest-prices-in-the-pan-india-auction-by-tea-board-of-india" class="text-center mx-auto mt-5"> <img style="filter: drop-shadow(0 10px 10px #0400004d);" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Tea_day_auction-mobile-banner.png?v=1659774584" alt="World Best Teas" class="text-center mx-auto lg-d-hide mt-4"> <img style="filter: drop-shadow(0 10px 10px #0400004d);" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/tea-day-auction-sinner-desktop-banner.png?v=1659774583" alt="World Best Teas" class="text-center mx-auto sm-d-hide mt-5"> </a>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/an-easy-mocktail-mar-tea-ni-for-a-pleasant-monsoon-evening</id>
    <published>2022-08-31T01:51:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:04:14-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/an-easy-mocktail-mar-tea-ni-for-a-pleasant-monsoon-evening"/>
    <title>An easy mocktail mar’tea’ni for a pleasant monsoon evening</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[If wellness choices have made you that ‘mocktail person’ at a party, here’s a way to spice things up for yourself! Who said you need to have a few cocktails to have fun, this mocktail mar’tea’ni is here to bust that myth.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/an-easy-mocktail-mar-tea-ni-for-a-pleasant-monsoon-evening">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center">
<div class="col-md-2 "><a href="https://www.traveldine.com/an-easy-mocktail-marteani-for-a-pleasant-monsoon-evening/" class="fancyboximg"><img class="img-fluid" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/traveldine.png?v=1661925935" width=""></a></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="https://www.traveldine.com/an-easy-mocktail-marteani-for-a-pleasant-monsoon-evening/" class="text-link">World tea News</a><span class="text-link"> </span>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Can you actually combine the techniques of a mocktail and the flavours of tea?</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">If wellness choices have made you that ‘mocktail person’ at a party, here’s a way to spice things up for yourself! Who said you need to have a few cocktails to have fun, this mocktail mar’tea’ni is here to bust that myth.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Made with the legendary Golden Tips Tea, this mocktail curated by Madhav Sarda is the best thing you’ll whip up. An expert Tea Taster and Managing Director at Golden Tips Tea, he’s curated the perfect fun yet comforting drink for you.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Established in 1933, Golden Tips Tea offers the world’s finest collection of teas worldwide. With over 10 stores and a chain of fabulous <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/pages/showrooms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tea Boutiques</a> in Darjeeling &amp; Sikkim, these teas are freshly packed and shipped almost immediately to be devoured in all their glory. According to industry sources, the <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/flavoured-teas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">flavoured tea</a> market growth is estimated at 45% per year in India. But of course, nothing beats the <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/earl-grey-teas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">classic Earl Grey</a>. Or in this case, the combination with pomegranate for a mocktail take on the classic martini.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">For Madhav Sarda, who was born and brought up in Darjeeling, tea is second nature. With over 4 decades of tea tasting experience majorly with <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/darjeeling" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Darjeeling</a> &amp; <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/assam" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Assam</a> orthodox teas, he’s particular about personally tasting and selecting each tea, assisted by his colleagues. It’s only the best of the best which eventually bears the Golden Tips stamp, to ensure that customers get the <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/all/perfect-cup-of-tea" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">perfect cup every time</a>.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">His passion to make Darjeeling Teas available to connoisseurs in India and worldwide – not only pure and fresh, but also at reasonable prices, and in attractive packaging directly from the source – continues unabated.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">This particular mar’tea’ni is a product of the same efforts, combining <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/all/flavour-for-every-reason-best-flavoured-teas-you-must-try" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the best flavours of tea</a> and the techniques of a classic cocktail. All to give you the perfect monsoon mocktail.</p>
<img class="d-block text-center mx-auto my-3" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/mocktail.png?v=1661926971" alt="" srcset="">
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Ingredients</h2>
<ul class="mt-0 mb-18">
<li class="mb-2 px-2">2 tbsp fresh pomegranate seeds</li>
<li class="mb-2 px-2">3-4 ginger juliennes</li>
<li class="mb-2 px-2">120-130 ml of Golden Tips Earl Grey Green Tea (An <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/green-teas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">orthodox Green tea</a> from Darjeeling and mildly scented with the natural oil of Bergamot)</li>
<li class="mb-2 px-2">Crushed ice cubes</li>
<li class="mb-2 px-2">60 ml pomegranate juice</li>
<li class="mb-2 px-2">10-15 ml fresh lemon juice</li>
<li class="mb-2 px-2">1 twig tulsi, for garnish</li>
</ul>
<div class="bg-light-green row sm-d-block img-150 align-items-center row-styling mt-4 mb-45">
<div class="col-md-9">
<h4 class="font-bold fs-24">Earl Grey Green Tea - Tin Can</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-1">An Unfermented orthodox Green tea from Darjeeling mildly scented with the natural oil of bergamot. Bergamot fruit is a pear-shaped sour orange originally found in south Italy. This fine &amp; mellow green tea is characteristic of a refreshing &amp; soothing taste, a fruity and fragrant citrus flavor &amp; light Colour in the cup.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-3 text-center mb-2">
<a target="_blank" class="text-decoration-none" href="/products/earl-grey-green-tea-tin-can-100gm?_pos=2&amp;_sid=838ce41f0&amp;_ss=r" rel="noopener noreferrer"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Earl-Grey-Green-Tea---Tin-Can_73c0d74d-56b3-4653-a19d-bb0d24639c32.png?v=1644828000" alt="Earl Grey Green Tea - Tin Can" class="img-fluid mb-3"> </a>
<div class="view-all mt-2 mb-4"><a target="_blank" class="seeallbutton text-link" href="/products/earl-grey-green-tea-tin-can-100gm?_pos=2&amp;_sid=838ce41f0&amp;_ss=r" rel="noopener noreferrer">View Price</a></div>
</div>
</div>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Method</h2>
<ul class="mt-0 mb-18">
<li class="mb-2 px-2">Brew the Golden Tips Earl Grey Green tea and let it cool down for 30 mins.</li>
<li class="mb-2 px-2">In a cocktail shaker, mix the lemon juice, ginger and pomegranate seeds.</li>
<li class="mb-2 px-2">Add crushed ice cubes, Golden Tips Earl Grey Green Tea and pomegranate juice.</li>
<li class="mb-2 px-2">Shake vigorously and strain the concoction into a martini glass.</li>
<li class="mb-2 px-2">Tip: Garnish the mocktail with tulsi leaves for that extra punch.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<a href="/blogs/all/bedtime-teas-for-better-sleep" class="d-none text-center mx-auto mt-5"> <img style="filter: drop-shadow(0 10px 10px #0400004d);" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/articles/fresh_green_tea-min_3f22779f-25ea-43f6-bb37-9bf14c61a321_1024x.jpg?v=1570714978" alt="World Best green Teas" class="text-center mx-auto lg-d-hide mt-4"> <img style="filter: drop-shadow(0 10px 10px #0400004d);" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/green-tea.jpg?v=1614291939" alt="World Best green Teas" class="text-center mx-auto sm-d-hide mt-5"> </a>
<!--RECIPE SCHEMA-->
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
	"@context": "http://schema.org/",
	"@type": "Recipe",
	"name": "AN EASY MOCKTAIL MAR’TEA’NI FOR A PLEASANT MONSOON EVENING",
	"image": [
		"https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/articles/Mocktail-GTT_2048x2048.png?v=1661927417"
	],
	"recipeCategory": "Beverages",
	"prepTime": "PT10M",
	"cookTime": "PT30M",
	"totalTime": "PT40M",
	"recipeYield": "2",
	"datePublished": "2022-08-31",
	"description": "mar’tea’ni is a product of the same efforts, combining the best flavours of tea and the techniques of a classic cocktail. All to give you the perfect monsoon mocktail.",
	"keywords": "mocktail,
",
	"author": {
		"@type": "Organization",
		"name": "Golden Tips Teas India"
	},
	"recipeIngredient": [
		"2 tbsp fresh pomegranate seeds",
		"3-4 ginger juliennes",
		"120-130 ml of Golden Tips Earl Grey Green Tea",
		"Crushed ice cubes",
		"60 ml pomegranate juice",
		"10-15 ml fresh lemon juice",
		"1 twig tulsi, for garnish"
	],
	"recipeInstructions": [
		{
			"@type": "HowToStep",
			"name": "Brew it",
			"text": "Brew the Golden Tips Earl Grey Green tea and let it cool down for 30 mins.",
			"url": "https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/all/an-easy-mocktail-mar-tea-ni-for-a-pleasant-monsoon-evening",
			"image": "https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/articles/Mocktail-GTT_2048x2048.png?v=1661927417"
		},
		{
			"@type": "HowToStep",
			"name": "Shake and Mix",
			"text": "In a cocktail shaker, mix the lemon juice, ginger and pomegranate seeds.",
			"url": "https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/all/an-easy-mocktail-mar-tea-ni-for-a-pleasant-monsoon-evening",
			"image": "https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/articles/Mocktail-GTT_2048x2048.png?v=1661927417"
		},
		{
			"@type": "HowToStep",
			"name": "Mx with the ice cubes",
			"text": "Add crushed ice cubes, Golden Tips Earl Grey Green Tea and pomegranate juice.",
			"url": "https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/all/an-easy-mocktail-mar-tea-ni-for-a-pleasant-monsoon-evening",
			"image": "https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/articles/Mocktail-GTT_2048x2048.png?v=1661927417"
		},
		{
			"@type": "HowToStep",
			"name": "Shake and Strain",
			"text": "Shake vigorously and strain the concoction into a martini glass.",
			"url": "https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/all/an-easy-mocktail-mar-tea-ni-for-a-pleasant-monsoon-evening",
			"image": "https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/articles/Mocktail-GTT_2048x2048.png?v=1661927417"
		},
		{
			"@type": "HowToStep",
			"name": "Garnish",
			"text": "Tip: Garnish the mocktail with tulsi leaves for that extra punch.",
			"url": "https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/all/an-easy-mocktail-mar-tea-ni-for-a-pleasant-monsoon-evening",
			"image": "https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/articles/Mocktail-GTT_2048x2048.png?v=1661927417"
		}
	]
}
</script>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/earl-grey-black-tea-is-popular-among-tea-lovers</id>
    <published>2022-08-01T05:35:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:04:22-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/earl-grey-black-tea-is-popular-among-tea-lovers"/>
    <title>Earl Grey Black tea is popular among tea lovers</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Madhav Sarda, MD of Golden Tips Tea, says that the flavoured tea market is growing at a fast clip in India.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/earl-grey-black-tea-is-popular-among-tea-lovers">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div id="dvContents" class="mt-4">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center">
<div class="col-md-2 "><a href="https://www.sundayguardianlive.com/news/earl-grey-black-tea-popular-among-tea-lovers" class="fancyboximg"><img class="img-fluid" style="background: black;" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2485/1434/files/logo13.png?v=1662968485" width=""></a></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22"> First published on <a href="https://www.sundayguardianlive.com/news/earl-grey-black-tea-popular-among-tea-lovers" class="text-link">Sunday Guardian Live</a><span class="text-link"> </span>; contributed by <a href="https://www.sundayguardianlive.com/news/earl-grey-black-tea-popular-among-tea-lovers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<h3>Madhav Sarda, MD of Golden Tips Tea, says that the flavoured tea market is growing at a fast clip in India.</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/flavoured-teas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flavoured teas</a> are particularly popular in India and worldwide. Known for <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/immunity-booster-teas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">boosting immunity</a>, these particular teas are now in demand post-pandemic. Madhav Sarda, Managing Director of Golden Tips Tea, said that Earl Grey Black tea is particularly favourite among tea lovers across the globe. Excerpts:</p>
<p><strong class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3 d-block">Q: According to you, what could be the future market growth of flavoured tea?</strong> Flavour in tea can be added in the form of spices, nuts, flowers, or flavour extracts such as essential oils of Bergamot, Lemon, Cranberry, Honey, Mint etc. With several organised players in the industry entering the fray, the flavoured tea market is growing at a fast clip in India. According to industry sources, flavoured tea market growth is estimated at 45% per year in India. As some reports suggest, the size of the flavoured tea market in India in terms of volume and price is approximately 60 million kgs and Rs 3,600 cr respectively. So, the flavoured tea market amounts to about 10% of the entire packaged tea consumption in India.</p>
<p><strong class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3 d-block">Q: Which flavour is higher in demand? Could you share some details on why customers favour that particular flavour?</strong> Earl Grey Black tea is by far the most popular flavoured tea from the Golden Tips stable. Apart from its numerous health benefits, the citrusy, aromatic and bold flavour of <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/collections/earl-grey-teas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Earl Grey tea</a> has made it a big favourite among tea lovers across the world. Earl Grey’s citrusy taste is due to the addition of natural Bergamot oil.</p>
<div class="row mb-5">
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20 mt-4">
<a class="text-center" href="/products/earl-grey-loose-leaf-black-tea?_pos=4&amp;_sid=9872ee2d3&amp;_ss=r"> <img class="mt-0" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/products/earl-grey_1024x.jpg?v=1648631375" alt="Earl Grey Loose Leaf Black Tea"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Earl Grey Loose Leaf Black Tea</p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="/products/earl-grey-loose-leaf-black-tea?_pos=4&amp;_sid=9872ee2d3&amp;_ss=r"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20 mt-4">
<a class="text-center" href="/products/earl-grey-spice-black-tea?_pos=6&amp;_sid=9872ee2d3&amp;_ss=r"> <img class="mt-0" alt="Earl Grey Spice Black Tea" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/products/JP-14Images-2_1_1024x.jpg?v=1654015425"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Earl Grey Spice Black Tea</p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="/products/earl-grey-spice-black-tea?_pos=6&amp;_sid=9872ee2d3&amp;_ss=r"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20 mt-4">
<a class="text-center" href="/products/earl-grey-green-tea-tin-can-100gm?_pos=7&amp;_sid=9872ee2d3&amp;_ss=r"> <img class="mt-0" alt="Earl Grey Tea - Tin Can" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/products/Earl-Grey-Green-Tea-Tin-Can-_100gm_1024x.jpg?v=1658566779"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Earl Grey Green Tea - Tin Can</p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="/products/earl-grey-green-tea-tin-can-100gm?_pos=7&amp;_sid=9872ee2d3&amp;_ss=r"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><strong class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3 d-block">Q: As Golden Tips Tea has plans to expand globally in a phased manner, which state or region (national and international) has higher demands for flavoured tea? Could share in detail about the growth in demand pre-pandemic and post-pandemic? </strong> Apart from the domestic market, our brand has dedicated customers across the globe and has shipped Golden Tips teas to almost 90 countries at some point of time in the last several years. Even though the distribution may not be very significant in terms of volume, the geographical spread is fairly noteworthy. Golden Tips also has exclusive representations in Russia, Japan, Mongolia, Taiwan, Nepal, Bhutan and now China, through distributors. Also, North America and Europe, particularly Russia have a fairly good demand for flavoured teas. Major factors driving the global market for flavoured tea include the easy availability of tea all over the world through various channels, especially online ones. Tea is exported all over the world and flavoured tea is receiving special attention in modern times, due to its added varieties and enhanced tastes. This is resulting in a surge in demand for flavoured tea across the globe. The demand for such functional teas has increased in India and globally particularly after the onset of Covid-19, as teas augmented with spices, fruits, nuts and natural herbs are known to boost immunity. Reports suggest that the moving annual total (MAT) of the packaged tea market in value is growing by around 19% in August 2021, over MAT August 2020 in India. Pre-pandemic, the growth was around 7% (2019 vs 2018).</p>
<p><strong class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3 d-block">Q: Has the economic crisis in Sri Lanka affected the growth of Golden Tips Tea?</strong> Plucking, processing and the final made tea are probably being stocked in Sri Lanka, and will eventually find their way to the market in spite of the current imbroglio. In the current situation, Sri Lanka is in dire need of US dollars and other hard currencies, and tea is one of their top forex earners. Hence, they are likely to do everything possible to ensure that their tea reaches the global markets and fetches the much-needed foreign exchange. Therefore, even if there may be some temporary minor benefits, significant long-term gains or benefits for Golden Tips emanating from the current socio-political scenario in Sri Lanka, are unlikely as exports will surely continue from that country.</p>
<p><strong class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3 d-block">Q: Due to the increased price rate, how do you plan to keep flavoured tea more affordable for the general public?</strong> As the prices of orthodox teas are spiralling, we are using broken and plain tea leaf varieties which have comparatively less character and are much cheaper than traditional made teas. The advantage of using these teas is that they are markedly less in price than full leaf teas and do not alter the taste of the tea in a significant manner.</p>
<p><strong class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3 d-block">Q: Where do you see Golden Tips Tea in 5 years?</strong> Golden Tips presently operates through its <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/pages/showrooms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">14 tea boutiques</a>, mostly in eastern India in Darjeeling, Mirik, Kalimpong, Gangtok, Bagdogra and Kolkata. Customers can buy our teas through our omni-channel routes like our website, <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.goldentipstea.com</a>, online marketplaces like Amazon and Flipkart, several leading retail chains and select distributor networks across several countries. In the next five years, Golden Tips has the potential to become one of the noteworthy global home-grown Indian tea brands with a strong focus on business ethics, quality, optimum pricing, customer centricity and sustainable supply chain practices.</p>
</div>
<!-- Single ad 3 -->]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/india-s-golden-tips-plans-broad-global-presence-thrives-locally-with-retail-shops-cafe</id>
    <published>2022-07-15T01:36:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:04:42-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/india-s-golden-tips-plans-broad-global-presence-thrives-locally-with-retail-shops-cafe"/>
    <title>India’s Golden Tips Plans Broad Global Presence, Thrives Locally with Retail Shops, Café</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[India’s Golden Tips, a tea brand from Darjeeling, is looking to expand its global footprint through e-commerce, strategic partnerships, and by widening its reach in global export markets through tie-ups overseas.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/india-s-golden-tips-plans-broad-global-presence-thrives-locally-with-retail-shops-cafe">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center mt-4">
<div class="col-md-2 "><a href="https://www.worldteanews.com/profiles/indias-golden-tips-plans-broad-global-presence-thrives-locally-retail-shops-cafe" class="fancyboximg"><img class="img-fluid" src="https://qtxasset.com/quartz/qcloud1/branding/worldteanews/wtn-logo21.svg?VersionId=5THqwBOOTUFFtBVbflZ0CaCdTTGtTtr." width=""></a></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="https://www.worldteanews.com/profiles/indias-golden-tips-plans-broad-global-presence-thrives-locally-retail-shops-cafe" class="text-link">World tea News</a><span class="text-link"> </span>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">India’s Golden Tips, a tea brand from Darjeeling, is looking to expand its global footprint through e-commerce, strategic partnerships, and by widening its reach in global export markets through tie-ups overseas.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">The brand has numerous retail outlets in the heart of Darjeeling and neighboring areas. “Over several decades, we have sourced, purchased and marketed the finest teas produced in Darjeeling,” said Madhav Sarda, a well-known tea taster and managing director of Golden Tips. “This has been our major contribution in bringing Darjeeling prominently on the world tea map."</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">For Sarda and Golden Tips, implementing new-age strategies and modifying the structure of the supply chain has proved to be beneficial. “Since digitization is the standard nowadays, using online channels of selling can boost the visibility and sales of tea brands,” he shared. “Also, since people are displaying an active interest in the purchase of premium teas online, online mediums could facilitate sales by providing a plethora of product information digitally, and thus increasing consumer knowledge and awareness.”</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Sarda said virtual platforms also enable easy-to-understand and often measurable insight into the patterns and preferences of the target customers and consumer behavior which can help to improve future product innovations and sale mechanisms.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Golden Tips operates mostly through its retail chains (14+ stores across Eastern India), its omni- channel route pan India, and through its website. It also recently opened its flagship tea café and restaurant, Teattoria in Darjeeling, which offers Italian/continental and Asian-inspired cuisine along with, of course, the brand’s own specialty teas.</p>
<img class="d-block text-center mx-auto my-5" src="https://qtxasset.com/quartz/qcloud1/styles/full_body_width/s3/media/image/2%20-%20Golden%20Tips%20-%20Darjeeling%20-%20Pic%205.jpg?VersionId=Vtzz6WNX2BFeQAhJ2f_KMq.Ix1h32TMS&amp;itok=SS4Rsj8o" alt="" srcset="">
<p class="custom-text mb-10">The company is focusing on broadening its presence in physical retail operations across metros of India by opening niche tea boutiques and stores. They’re also looking at commissioning a few outlets once the COVID-19 pandemic fully subsides.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Apart from the domestic market, the company has dedicated customers across the globe and has shipped Golden Tips teas to almost 90 countries over the last several years via orders from its website and online channels.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">For business development, Golden Tips has exclusive representations in Russia, Japan, Mongolia, Taiwan, Nepal, Bhutan and now China – all through distributors.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Indeed, Darjeeling tea is a sought-after tea by connoisseurs and avid tea-drinkers around the globe. The one-of-a-kind taste of Darjeeling teas comes from its unique terroir, along with the intricacies of harvesting and processing. Though Darjeeling constitutes only 0.1 percent of the world’s tea production, it is known for its distinctive flavor and aroma, which is unique only to the region.Sarda noted that Assam is a fairly important market for Golden Tips in both CTC and loose-leaf tea categories.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">“We operate primarily from Darjeeling; however, we also procure good quality teas from Assam through specialty auctions and few producers,” Sarda said.</p>
<img class="d-block text-center mx-auto my-5" src="https://qtxasset.com/quartz/qcloud1/styles/full_body_width/s3/media/image/2%20-%20Golden%20Tips%20-%20Darjeeling%20-%20Pic%202%20-%20Golden%20Tips%20Tea%20Boutique.jpg?VersionId=aWdx3qBZjSjP.HdasJci2GwecHnhthXV&amp;itok=P_crRDMc" alt="" srcset="">
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Golden Tips's expertise lies in packaging premium teas in multiple variants, sizes, colors and assortments, thereby giving a plethora of choices to the customers to pick their teas from. “We facilitate free tea-tasting sessions in all our tea boutiques, thereby making it easier for international and domestic buyers to have easy access to our offerings and select the teas of their choice,” Sarda said.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Factoring in the Supply Chain, Sustainability into Golden Tips’ Business</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">While climate and sustainability is certainly very important for Golden Tips, the influence of supply chains on the price of tea cannot be ignored. “In India, the world’s second largest producer of tea, the COVID-19 pandemic has wreaked havoc on the industry,” shared Sarda. “Social distancing measures have not only prevented some workers from harvesting tea but also disturbed trucking services. On top of that, port closures have sparked shipping delays and halted exports of tea. Meanwhile, the country’s logistics operations are also suffering due to a lack of equipment.”</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Looking at other issues the business faces, Sarda said that tea leaves are continually being harvested, resulting in the loss of nutrients in the leaves, so nutrients must be continually added in order for tea to continue being harvested.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">“Unfortunately, natural and ecologically-friendly fertilizers are not the norm in the tea industry,” revealed Sarda. “These fertilizers can lead to a number of problems, though small amounts of these nutrients are beneficial on land. Over fertilization can also result in soil acidification and contamination of water supplies with nitrates.”</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Gradual changes in temperature and rainfall patterns in Darjeeling hills is also beginning to affect production of the famous Darjeeling tea. “The maximum temperature in Kurseong has risen by 0.51 degree over the last 20 years, while total annual rainfall dropped by 56 mm and relative humidity by 16.07 percent, leading to a decline in overall production of Darjeeling tea in terms of green leaf production per hectare,” Sarda said.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Growing Brand Consciousness for Golden Tips</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">As gifting tea packages at corporate events, weddings, etc. has become a common trend, brand consciousness has come into play on a larger scale for Golden Tips. People are now progressively opting for branded labels instead of products from the “unorganized sector.”</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">“This has led to increased global investment in tea brands who have a compelling story to tell and with a scalable business model,” said Sarda.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">As per Nielsen’s insights, Indian consumers these days look at food labels more than ever before and are willing to pay more for products that make the cut, especially those with added nutrients. They are also more loyal to trusted brands.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">“The surge in brand preference has also come because of the inclination towards health and hygiene factors, since people generally expect a product to be premium and reliable if it is branded,” Sarda noted.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Golden Tips’ Teattoria Is a Hit, Tea Café Chains Are Emerging</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">The brand’s Teattoria restaurant, nestled in one corner in a main promenade of Darjeeling and adjacent to the Golden Tips Tea Boutique, Chowrasta, has a uniquely conceptualized outdoor serving area overlooking the majestic mountains.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">The view on a clear day – or even on a clouded one – is alluring and mesmerizing with lilting and music to win one's heart. The venue also overlooks Chowrasta, the city center on the other side. The eatery also features a classy and well-furnished indoor fine-dining area to seat 30 to 35 people, and it also offers brilliant views of the nature outside.</p>
<img class="d-block text-center mx-auto my-5" src="https://qtxasset.com/quartz/qcloud1/styles/full_body_width/s3/media/image/2%20-%20Golden%20Tips%20-%20Darjeeling%20-%20Pic%203%20-%20Crowds%20Enjoying%20Lunch%20at%20Golden%20Tips%20Teattoria.jpg?VersionId=04_9h888SixrvXkrIvGwKIfdHXD4b1g3&amp;itok=z0VN3WWo" alt="">
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Sarda says tea café chains emerging across India are giving consumers a midway option between at-home consumption and the humble roadside stall. A number of companies with tea outlets similar to modern coffee chains have mushroomed and are slowly revolutionizing the tea industry in India.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">“These companies are looking to appeal to young Indians by offering them an upgraded version of the tea ‘Dhabas’ and their efforts are paying off. Some of these startups are now national chains," said Sarda, who believes these tea chains are a much better alternative to the open-air tea vendors in India, offering consumers a more relaxed environment with seating and snacks.</p>
</div>
<a href="/blogs/all/bedtime-teas-for-better-sleep" class="d-none text-center mx-auto mt-5"> <img style="filter: drop-shadow(0 10px 10px #0400004d);" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/articles/fresh_green_tea-min_3f22779f-25ea-43f6-bb37-9bf14c61a321_1024x.jpg?v=1570714978" alt="World Best green Teas" class="text-center mx-auto lg-d-hide mt-4"> <img style="filter: drop-shadow(0 10px 10px #0400004d);" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/green-tea.jpg?v=1614291939" alt="World Best green Teas" class="text-center mx-auto sm-d-hide mt-5"> </a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/tea-tourism-the-hot-new-engine-of-growth-for-darjeeling-s-economy</id>
    <published>2022-06-20T07:32:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:04:34-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/tea-tourism-the-hot-new-engine-of-growth-for-darjeeling-s-economy"/>
    <title>TEA TOURISM : THE HOT NEW ENGINE OF GROWTH FOR DARJEELING’S ECONOMY</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Some people travel for leisure, many people travel for food and some travel for both</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/tea-tourism-the-hot-new-engine-of-growth-for-darjeeling-s-economy">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center">
<div class="col-md-2 "><img class="img-fluid" src="https://travelspan.in/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/output-onlinepngtools-1.png" width=""></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="https://travelspan.in/tea-tourism-the-hot-new-engine-of-growth-for-darjeelings-economy/">Travel Span</a><span class="text-link"> </span>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><strong>Why Shouldn’t Darjeeling be everyone’s cup of tea </strong><br>Some people travel for leisure, many people travel for food and some travel for both. So, it would be fair to say that there would be people who travel for the drink that many of us just can’t do without, first thing in the morning. There are few better places to savour a cup of tea than at a tea plantation, close to the land where the leaves were plucked from, overlooking verdant hillsides and picturesque valleys. India has a plethora of stays for tea lovers, mostly estates from yesteryears which have been refurbished into quaint homestays.</p>
<p>In the British era, Darjeeling was one of the favourite retreats for the officers. With its quaint colonial charm and endless green stretches of lush tea plantations, the region has been a favourite for people who have yearned to do away with city life for some time, and get lost in magical natural beauty. Nowadays, estates have started adding varied experiences like horse riding, nature trains, visit to local families, cultural evenings, among other things. Hence, Tea tourism provides travellers with the opportunity to interact with nature, wildlife and simultaneously extract the goodness of socio-cultural diversity of the region. </p>
<p>People can learn about local cultures by getting a first-hand account of the rituals and ceremonies. Boosting rural tourism will help solve socio-economic problems and alleviate the livelihoods of denizens. </p>
<p>It would not be incorrect to state that tea tourism can alter the tea drinking experience entirely by helping us understand the origins, processing, and terroir of tea in an intellectual manner. It can engage sensorially – we can touch the dew laden tea leaves and smell the earthiness of the soil in which it grows. Sometimes to taste the best tea, you just need to have a sense of adventure. </p>
<p>With the government allowing tea garden owners to use a part of their unused land for the purpose of tea tourism, there is also a growing need to educate tea estate owners, guides, and travel agencies on the benefits of tea tourism. </p>
<p><strong>The Challenges</strong>: – Tea tourism in India is still in its nascent stage. Given our colonial history and our own rich legacy, India has immense potential to offer a robust tea-tasting and tourism experience. However, it lacks proper structure, policy and marketing initiatives.       <br>Detailed planning is required for making tea tourism more attractive in India. The Tea Board and the Tourism ministry at the Centre can join hands to play a crucial role in this endeavour. Tea companies too should come forward and aim to promote Eco-Tourism by devoting land which is not feasible for plantation tea for multifarious tea-related activities, and setting up resorts and homestays. </p>
<p>This will boost the economy of the region by creating new jobs, increasing revenues of all stakeholders, improve infrastructure and plant a sense of cultural exchange between visitors and locals. </p>
<p>Organising Tea Festivals in the tea gardens, visits to Tea Boutiques located at nearby towns where exotic teas, tea wares &amp; souvenirs are on display, will further drive interest in such tea tourism. </p>
<p>Tea gastronomy could be highlighted with the promotion of Teainfused drinks &amp; beverages, confectionery, food and this could further add to the many lucrative avenues for the areas around the tea estate. These steps could help promote, upgrade &amp; highlight the consumption of teas as well as their multi-health benefits, which fall within the ambit of Tea Tourism. </p>
<p>Most of the above measures can inject a much-needed impetus to the Tea Tourism industry, tea trade in general, rural areas scattered around tea plantations, tourist guides &amp; interpreters, manufacturers &amp; dealers of tea accessories etc. However, there needs to be a concerted effort involving all stakeholders to move ahead in this direction. </p>
<p>Lastly, the pandemic has led people to search for more isolated and secluded spots, which has slowly resulted in more and more people being interested in these beautifully preserved estates. This accounts for the rise in Indian tourists visiting tea estates, which were predominantly popular with foreigners. This momentum needs not only to be preserved but also to be accelerated further. </p>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/trend-of-mushrooming-cafes-and-bakeries-alongside-tea-boutiques</id>
    <published>2022-06-20T07:03:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:04:30-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/trend-of-mushrooming-cafes-and-bakeries-alongside-tea-boutiques"/>
    <title>Trend of Mushrooming Cafes and Bakeries alongside Tea Boutiques</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Like a bolt from the blue, the Covid pandemic has changed the world forever. A new normal has emerged in almost every aspect of life.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/trend-of-mushrooming-cafes-and-bakeries-alongside-tea-boutiques">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center">
<div class="col-md-2 "><img class="img-fluid" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/ET-Hospitality-World.png?v=1653980463" width=""></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="https://hospitality.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/speaking-heads/trend-of-mushrooming-cafes-and-bakeries-alongside-tea-boutiques/92200414">H</a><span class="text-link"><a href="https://hospitality.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/speaking-heads/trend-of-mushrooming-cafes-and-bakeries-alongside-tea-boutiques/92200414">ospitality World</a> </span>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="custom-container px-2">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center">
<div class="col-md-12">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22"><span>Like a bolt from the blue, the Covid pandemic has changed the world forever. A new normal has emerged in almost every aspect of life. This has resulted in tea retail brands to tweak their business strategy and start opening bakeries and cafes alongside their boutiques to cater to popular demand.</span></p>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Tea is one of the most loved beverages in India and across the world. PM Modi’s “tea connection” has caught the imagination of an entire generation. People have enjoyed tea since time immemorial and consider it to be one of the most cherished parts of their native culture. The love of Indian audiences for this super beverage has given the tea industry a loyal customer base in the country.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">According to expertmarketresearch.com, the Indian tea industry is expected to grow at a CAGR of about 4.2% in the 2021-26 period and reach an approximate valuation of 1.40 million tonnes by the end of this period.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 "> </p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Like a bolt from the blue, the Covid pandemic has changed the world forever. A new normal has emerged in almost every aspect of life. This has resulted in tea retail brands to tweak their business strategy and start opening bakeries and cafes alongside their boutiques to cater to popular demand. Not surprisingly, branded tea cafes are frothing up across India’s cities, as an upgrade to the ubiquitous CHAI stalls.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">These cafes are located either adjacent to, or within the tea boutiques themselves. They are offering specialized tea mocktails and snacks like cookies, macarons and sandwiches to guests along with premium teas. This combination is a hugely popular concept brewing all over India.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 "> </p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">As per a study by Numr Research, about 443 million Indian millennials spend more than Rs 4,000 on their wellness and experiential activities every month. They form the largest group of consumers who will drive consumer demand and result in economic growth in the next decade. They are in fact, accentuating this trend of opening tea bars alongside tea boutiques.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Earlier, tea stalls were a common sight across India, but they were fragmented and unorganised. Tea café chains like the one started by Golden Tips are emerging across India and giving consumers a midway option between at-home consumption and the humble roadside stall. These tea cafes offer a comfortable alternative as against roadside tea vendors and which provide people a more relaxed setting, with proper seating and snacks.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 "> </p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Another narrative worth a thought is that coffee is not a common man’s beverage in India and which allowed cafés to position coffee as trendy and as a consequence of which, coffee outlets became aspirational places. They offered a chic ambience, with an assortment of beverages, snacks along with free wi-fi, and thus became hangout areas for college going crowds and young professionals. Tea companies tried to copy this model, but initially it did not take off since tea is a common man’s drink in India. As a result, tea brands quickly moved towards enhancing the overall tea-drinking experience for the customer by opening plush tea bars.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 "> More importantly, they have positioned themselves as casual Vis-à-vis coffee shops’ sophistication, encouraging customers to make multiple visits a day in contrast to coffee chains. This is in line with how tea is seen in India – as a people’s drink consumed - sweet, milky or even without milk - several times a day.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 "> </p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Post Covid, this homage to Indian roots is mainly what tea companies are bringing to the table in a contemporary setting. This shift in strategy appears to be paying off for the tea brands. Providing more varied options than coffee chains at lower price, goes a long way in appealing to consumers, especially experience-hungry millennials.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">For example, a cup of MASALA CHAI at Golden Tips tea bar is priced at INR 80 with complimentary cookies as well, whilst the cheapest coffee at Starbucks could set you off by INR 200 or more. Targeting Millennials is not surprising, since almost a third of the country’s population is in the 15- 35 age group, who are also likely to share their experiences on social media and other platforms.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 "> </p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Meanwhile, personalisation is a major selling point for Golden Tips tea bars. Customers can choose from our eclectic variety of teas and a range of herbs and spices at reasonable rates. With these options of customising their tea, patrons can conjure up a cuppa that appeals to their palate and preference.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">This highlights the need for brands to constantly reinvent themselves to reach out to newer customers, not only with product innovations but also with formats that cater to changing times and needs. This can go a long way in acquiring new audiences without alienating traditional brand loyalists.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 "> </p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 "><em>Madhav Sarda is the expert tea taster and managing director of tea retail brand Golden Tips Tea</em></p>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/russia-ukraine-war-won-t-have-much-impact-on-indian-tea-industry</id>
    <published>2022-05-24T02:23:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:04:45-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/russia-ukraine-war-won-t-have-much-impact-on-indian-tea-industry"/>
    <title>‘Russia-Ukraine war won’t have much impact on Indian tea industry’</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="mb-4">After having sold 1st flush tea from our estate in auction for Rs 23,000 per kg, with good monsoon projections ahead, we are also bullish about 2nd flush Darjeeling tea, says Madhav Sarda, MD, Golden Tips Tea</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/russia-ukraine-war-won-t-have-much-impact-on-indian-tea-industry">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center mt-4">
<div class="col-md-2"><img class="img-fluid" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/hans-india-logo.png?v=1653376636" width=""></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="https://www.thehansindia.com/business/russia-ukraine-war-wont-have-much-impact-on-indian-tea-industry-742964" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">The Hansindia</a>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 mt-3">Darjeeling-based leading tea retailer- Golden Tips recently came to the limelight after it had purchased <a target="_blank" class="link-styling-blog text-link" href="/collections/white" rel="noopener noreferrer">organic white tea</a>, a special variety of the beverage, at Rs 23,000 per kilogram and 'Moonlight' tea at Rs 21,000 per kg from Goodricke's Badamtam estate in Darjeeling. The prices are the season's highest so far. Tea retailer Golden Tips plans to expand its footprint through the e-commerce route by entering into strategic partnerships in the country and widening its reach in export markets through distributor tie-ups overseas. Speaking to Bizz Buzz exclusively, Madhav Sarda, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea, and an expert tea taster, decodes what is often known and described as the ‘champagne of tea’</p>
<h4 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">According to the Indian Tea Association (ITA), annual production of <a target="_blank" class="link-styling-blog text-link" href="/collections/darjeeling" rel="noopener noreferrer">Darjeeling tea</a> has drastically fallen from 12 million kg to six million kg, with the primary reason being difficulty in replantation due to the hilly terrain and lack of expansion of the cultivation area in the region. Has the output fallen substantially or alarmingly? What is your take on this?</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">See, you will have to keep in mind that tea production (both quality and quantity) needs nice and warm sunshine and at the same time good rainfall. If there is a shortfall of either of the two, both quality and quantity drop. The tea output in the period that you mentioned, had gone down thanks to a dry spell and as there was no precipitation. Rains started very late and bushes were not flushing. Although the output had fallen initially due to lower rainfall, it subsequently picked up. Now it’s almost normal. However, having said this, one must remember that there is nothing like ‘making up for production losses’. Whatever has been lost, has been lost.</p>
<br>
<h4 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">Darjeeling tea is only a minuscule percentage of the domestic and overseas tea market. Do you see this growing substantially, going forward?</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Darjeeling tea is only a 7 million kg market (all varieties taken together). So, the good quality Darjeeling tea market is even smaller. Ironically many people are finding it easy, convenient, and making more business sense in focussing on <a target="_blank" class="link-styling-blog text-link" href="/blogs/all/tea-tourism" rel="noopener noreferrer">tea tourism</a>, and tea resorts, than concentrating on producing good quality Darjeeling tea.</p>
<h4 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">Do you think that the Sri Lankan crisis can be a blessing in disguise for the Indian tea sector, Sri Lanka being one of the largest exporters of tea in the global market?</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">See, tea plantations, plucking- everything has been done in Sri Lanka and they will have to be sent to the market. Especially in the current situation, they are in dire need of dollars or other hard currencies. And tea is one of their top forex earners. So they will do everything possible and make sure that their tea reaches the global market and fetches foreign exchange. Therefore, even if there are some minor benefits, I don’t think there will be some significant or long-term gains or benefits for us. Exports will continue from that country.</p>
<h4 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">How would the ongoing Russia-Ukraine war impact the Indian tea industry?</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">The overall tea exports had also fallen. Tea exports were lower due to a shortage of shipping containers and high ocean freight. Tea exports fell to 195.50 million kg in the 2021 calendar year from 209.72 million in 2020, according to Tea Board statistics. And subsequently, tea exports declined by 2.4 percent to 184.35 million kg during the April-February period of the last fiscal, according to the latest Tea Board data.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">The shipment of the crop stood at 188.91 million kg in the corresponding period of the previous year. When it comes to Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS) countries, including Russia and Ukraine, in particular, they imported 41.18 million kg, the highest among the overseas destinations of Indian tea, during the period under review from 46.19 million in the year-earlier period. Among the CIS bloc, Russia was the main importer with a shipment of 31.88 million kg in the April- February period of 2021-22, down from 33.65 million kg in the same period the previous year.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">But I think these are all temporary setbacks and they happened because both the transport route and payment routes came under the shadow. Although India continues to enjoy the best relationship with Russia, it has taken a non-committed and impartial stand in this armed conflict. India is also taking a role in mutually settling the conflicts. India is going ahead with its plans on the economic and business front. So, I think the conflicts will be resolved in due time. Unless there are further escalations, I don’t think we have reasons to be too much worried about this.</p>
<h4 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">The tea industry has been seeking and demanding a special financial package from the Centre for retaining the viability of plantation activity, which is now under ‘threat,’ according to the industry. What is your take on this?</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Although the industry, in general, has been demanding this, personally I don’t think that anything is going to come. On the contrary, whatever little sops and other facilities we have been getting here and there, may gradually be taken away. That’s the trend. Personally, I also have a feeling that the moment we get anything we start to ask for more. We should rather strive to be self-reliant and self-sufficient.</p>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/ex-jammu-and-kashmir-cm-farooq-abdullah-visits-golden-tips-tea-boutique-located-in-chowrasta-darjeeling</id>
    <published>2022-05-17T00:39:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:05:43-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/ex-jammu-and-kashmir-cm-farooq-abdullah-visits-golden-tips-tea-boutique-located-in-chowrasta-darjeeling"/>
    <title>Ex Jammu and Kashmir CM Farooq Abdullah visits Golden Tips Tea boutique located in Chowrasta, Darjeeling.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="mb-4">9th May, 2022 – Ex Jammu and Kashmir CM Farooq Abdullah recently visited Golden Tips Tea boutique located in Chowrasta, Darjeeling. He savoured premium quality Moonlight Spring Teas in the premises.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/ex-jammu-and-kashmir-cm-farooq-abdullah-visits-golden-tips-tea-boutique-located-in-chowrasta-darjeeling">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2">
    <div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center mt-4">
    <div class="col-md-2 "><img class="img-fluid" src="https://www.prittleprattlenews.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/PP-News-Logo-Featuring-you-virtuously_280.png" width=""></div>
    <div class="col-md-10">
    <p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold  fs-22">First published on <a href="https://www.prittleprattlenews.com/food/ex-jammu-and-cm-farooq/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Prittle Prattle News</a></p>
    </div>
    </div>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold">9th May, 2022 – Ex Jammu and Kashmir CM Farooq Abdullah recently visited Golden Tips Tea boutique located in Chowrasta, Darjeeling. He savoured premium quality Moonlight Spring Teas in the premises. Mr Abdullah appreciated the tea boutique, the picturesque ambience of Cafe <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/pages/teattoria" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link"> Teattoria</a>, and bought some premium teas too. He interacted with the staff earnestly, and showed keen interest in the eclectic variety of Single Origin, Blends and Tea Accessories on display in the store.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10 mt-3">Golden Tips comes with a heritage of 80+ years and 4 generations. The company follows the (Direct from Plantation + Auction model) and their expertise lies in sourcing, packaging and marketing of premium quality single origin teas, and tea blends. Apart from the domestic market, they export teas to 90+ countries with Russia, Japan, Mongolia, Nepal, Bhutan and now China being their main international markets.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">When the company started a few decades back, the almost complete absence of a premium homegrown brand that could package and present the finest <a class="text-link" href="/collections/darjeeling">Darjeeling Teas</a>  to customers spurred us to start Golden Tips. The endeavour has been to cater to domestic as well as foreign customers, especially those visiting India, through their 14+ tea boutiques, omni-channel presence across India (Bombay Stores/ Foodhall/ Nilgiris/ Central Cottage Industries Emporia, Dorabjee, Lulu, Pothy’s etc.) and through <a href="/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link"> our website</a> and marketplaces like Amazon and Flipkart.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">Golden Tips has a vast and eclectic range of the finest Darjeeling, Assam and other Indian teas sourced from the best plantations across the country. These teas are packaged in varied styles and packs. Like Economy packs, Handcrafted Gift packs consisting of hand-carved wooden boxes, fancy Brocade and Velvet cloth bags, Jute boxes, etc. They also manufacture Commercial packs in Paper Cartons and Tin Cans, which encloses the premium teas.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">The first flush Darjeeling tea of the new season has set a new record price of Rs 23,000 per kg. Golden Tips obtained and purchased these new season spring teas from Goodricke Group- The Badamtam Tea Estate. The company paid Rs 23,000 per kg for Organic White tea and Rs 21,000 per kg for Moonlight tea, the highest prices of the season so far. Golden Tips purchased 10 kilograms of Organic White tea and 5 kilograms of Moonlight tea. These teas were picked just a few days ago from the estate at an elevation of around 4,500 feet above sea level, giving them a distinct character and quality.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">Madhav Sarda, Managing Director Golden Tips Tea, and Well Known Tea Taster said, “We are glad to once again procure the most exotic spring teas from the Goodricke Group’s Badamtam tea estate. Surging demand for these teas in the overseas market and increased palate for premium spring flush teas in the domestic scenario prompted us to procure the teas at higher than normal prices. Our relationship with Goodricke Group goes beyond the procurement of teas, the common vision of providing a world-class tea experience to tea lovers all over the world, has made us natural partners.”</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">The tea retailer plans to expand its footprint through the e-commerce route by entering into strategic partnerships in the country and widen its reach in export markets through distributor tie-ups overseas.</p>
<!-- 
    <p class="custom-text mb-10 mt-3">Golden Tips has a vast and eclectic range of the finest <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/darjeeling" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Darjeeling</a>, <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/sikkim" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sikkim</a>, <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/assam" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Assam</a>, <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/nilgiri" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nilgiris</a>, and other Indian teas sourced from the best plantations across the country. These teas are packaged in varied styles and packs. Like Economy packs, Handcrafted Gift packs consisting of <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/wooden-jute-boxes" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">hand-carved wooden boxes</a>, <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/brocade-bags" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fancy Brocade</a> and Velvet cloth bags, Jute boxes, etc. The brand also manufactures commercial packs in paper cartons and tin cans, as also gift packaging and assortments.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">Madhav, who is also an experienced tea taster, shares, “Many of the offerings that we have are Organic like our 2nd Flush Ruby Regalia Black Tea from the famous Arya Tea Estate, Organic Moonlight White Tea etc., amongst a host of other exotic teas. However, presently, we are not using the Certified Organic tag, though Golden Tips is certified by IMO India (IMO India is an independent certification body for Organic Agriculture that has been carrying out audits and certification since 1995) and is also JAS (Japanese Agriculture Standard) Certified which ensures we comply with JAS Standards established by the Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries, Japan. We plan to launch our initial Certified Organic variants this year.”</p>
    <h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Sustainable sourcing</h2>
    <div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-6">
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">Is a magical land of ingredients. All of these products have strong wellness connotations that have been accepted by people globally. India grows about 25 % of the world’s tea in addition to exotic herbs, spices, and superfoods, like Turmeric, Moringa, Ashwagandha, Tulsi, and Giloy.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">Madhav points out, “Our teas are freshly sourced from the picturesque tea gardens of Darjeeling, Assam, Kangra, Sikkim, and Nilgiris. So, our ingredients (Teas and Spices) are all sourced from within the country, with some being sourced sustainably too.”</p>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-6">
    <div class="text-center"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Sustainable_sourcing.jpg?v=1645080850" alt="Finest Teas" class="img-fluid" srcset="" /></div>
    </div>
    </div>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10 mt-3">Darjeeling Tea received the GI tag in 2004. This tag ensures that tea grown just in the district of Darjeeling can be sold as Darjeeling. Besides, none other than those registered as authorized users by the Tea Board are allowed to use the popular product name. Madhav observes, “The acquisition of this Tag has had a positive fall-out in the region as it fetches a slightly premium price for the plantation owners, and hence a ripple effect percolates down to the tea workers even though a lot more needs to be done by the Government. Darjeeling Tea has been able to maintain an even curve when the tea sector at large has gone through a low phase owing to strikes and climate change. It has also brought about the consolidation of ownership and new investments in the tea industry of the region.”</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">Elucidating on the future roadmap for Golden Tips, Madhav says, “We have recently opened our flagship Tea Café and restaurant “Teattoria” in Darjeeling. It offers Italian/ Continental and Oriental cuisine along with our Specialty Teas. We now plan to expand our footprint through our offline/ physical retail operations across Metro and Tier 2 cities in India by opening niche experiential tea boutiques and stores. We are exploring this route and hopefully shall finalize some tie-ups after the current wave of the pandemic subsides. We also intend to give a thrust to our online operations to capture a larger market in the near future.”</p>
    </div>
    <a class="d-block mt-5" href="/collections/darjeeling"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/yes-mobile_1800x_c3c5919a-0d60-48dc-8928-aa8905f5407b.jpg?v=1633082296" alt="Darjeeling Tea" class="text-center mx-auto lg-d-hide" /> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/say_yes_to_darjeeling.jpg?v=1633082296%5C" alt="Darjeeling Teas" class="text-center mx-auto sm-d-hide" /> </a> -->
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/emergence-of-tea-from-a-beverage-to-a-wellness-superfood</id>
    <published>2022-03-30T04:41:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:04:49-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/emergence-of-tea-from-a-beverage-to-a-wellness-superfood"/>
    <title>Emergence Of Tea From A Beverage To A Wellness Superfood</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="mb-4">Anyone can drink tea without having any toxic side effects. And, in a gradually evolving scenario, it is emerging as the new superfood for health-conscious people.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/emergence-of-tea-from-a-beverage-to-a-wellness-superfood">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2 mt-4">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center">
<div class="col-md-2"><img class="img-fluid" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/The-Health-Site.png?v=1648630231" width=""></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="https://www.thehealthsite.com/fitness/diet/emergence-of-tea-from-a-beverage-to-a-wellness-superfood-867728/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">The Health Site</a>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 mt-3 font-bold">Anyone can drink tea without having any toxic side effects. And, in a gradually evolving scenario, it is emerging as the new superfood for health-conscious people.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Due to the ongoing COVID pandemic situation, there is a huge resurgence of teas with proven health benefits. <a href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas" target="_blank" class="text-link" rel="noopener noreferrer">Immunity-boosting teas</a> and superfoods with Ayurvedic ingredients like Turmeric, Ashwagandha, Moringa, Tulsi, etc are in big demand. As per a study by Numr Research, about 443 million Indian millennials spend more than Rs 4000 on their health and wellness every month. Both established companies and start-ups have caught on to this trend and have witnessed phenomenal growth. There is an increasing trend globally among people aged between 20 and 45 to shift towards immunity-boosting wellness branded tea. Such a shift would contribute to the growth of the wellness industry in India too. With immunity-boosting teas enriched with Ayurvedic ingredients readily available online and in brick-and-mortar stores, customers are spoilt for choices. So, it would not be a misnomer to say that augmented nutrition will be the mantra in 2022.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Immunity boosting premium tea</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">In this scenario, the demand for <a href="/collections/all" target="_blank" class="text-link" rel="noopener noreferrer">premium teas</a> has increased. These premium teas include specialty and <a href="/collections/flavoured-teas" target="_blank" class="text-link" rel="noopener noreferrer">flavored teas</a> that boost immunity and the younger generation are lapping them up. 2022 will see many new normals emerging. Mindful eating and mindful drinking will be a trend, which will be increasingly followed by citizens to improve their health and wellbeing. Mindfulness teaches us how to rely on our body's inherent ability to tell us when we are hungry or full, thirsty or not too.</p>
<div class="row mb-5">
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20 mt-4">
<a class="text-center" href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas/products/herbyoga-desi-kadha-herbal-tea-immunity-booster-kadha-tea"> <img class="mt-0" alt="Herbyoga - Immunity Booster Desi Kadha Tea" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/products/D-kadha_1024x.jpg?v=1622696287"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Herbyoga - Immunity Booster Desi Kadha Tea</p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas/products/herbyoga-desi-kadha-herbal-tea-immunity-booster-kadha-tea"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20 mt-4">
<a class="text-center" href="/products/darjeeling-earl-grey-tea-tin-can-100gm"> <img class="mt-0" alt="Earl Grey Tea - Tin Can" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/products/Untitled-8_a4401c9f-d0e1-484c-a753-29dd3dffa397_1024x.jpg?v=1637677157"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Earl Grey Tea - Tin Can</p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="/products/darjeeling-earl-grey-tea-tin-can-100gm"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20 mt-4">
<a class="text-center" href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas/products/empyrean-azure-green-tea"> <img class="mt-0" alt="mpyrean Azure - Blue Tea Infusion" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/products/JGFKF_1024x.jpg?v=1622635499"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Empyrean Azure - Blue Tea Infusion</p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas/products/empyrean-azure-green-tea"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Tea as a superfood</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Now, back to the question of whether tea is indeed a superfood. As mentioned before, although this term itself is mostly used for marketing purposes rather than as a scientific definition, it can essentially be used to describe foods that contain disease-preventing active ingredients, such as the catechins found in tea. So, in this sense, tea could indeed be considered a superfood. For one thing, tea has been associated with the prevention of many of the major diseases that are huge health problems nowadays.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Regular tea intake can lower diabetes, cancer risk</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">It is known that people who drink tea regularly have a <a href="/blogs/all/tea-help-in-fighting-cancer" target="_blank" class="text-link" rel="noopener noreferrer">reduced incidence of diabetes and cancer</a>. The exact mechanisms of action by which tea decreases the occurrence of these diseases are not yet fully understood, and some scientists do not believe tea helps to prevent diseases at all, so whether tea can actually fight diseases or not is still under debate. Nevertheless, given that both cancer and diabetes may involve free radicals, it is possible that antioxidant compounds, such as the catechins in tea, do have the ability to block free radicals and help prevent these diseases.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">It keeps metabolism kicking</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Superfoods are typically nutrient-dense, and so is tea. Along with catechins, tea also has minerals (such as manganese) and amino acids that are necessary for our metabolism. Thus, drinking tea can easily be seen as a good habit for maintaining health and wellness.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Variety, availability makes this a good choice</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Most superfoods have one drawback, and that is that they are not easily found everywhere in the world. However, tea is readily found all around the world nowadays. It can be brought from supermarkets and in many other places. There are many varieties of tea to choose from, depending on the <a href="/blogs/all/10-tea-gifts-for-tea-lovers" target="_blank" class="text-link" rel="noopener noreferrer">tea drinker's</a> preference for aroma and taste. Tea can be easily prepared in any household it is just a matter of adding hot water and maybe a little bit of sugar to mask the bitterness.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Side effects of drinking tea</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Anyone can drink tea without having any toxic side effects. Some superfoods have negative side effects when they are eaten in large quantities, but tea does not have this drawback. However, having said all that, everything should be consumed in moderation, and thus, drinking tea should be done with a certain level of balance as well.</p>
</div>
<a class="d-block mt-5" href="/blogs/all/biggest-collection-of-high-immunity-teas"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/top-immunity-teas-mob.png?v=1648632425" alt="Darjeeling Tea" class="text-center mx-auto lg-d-hide"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/top-immunity-teas.png?v=1648632425" alt="Immunity Booster Teas" class="text-center mx-auto sm-d-hide"> </a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/new-trends-defining-the-tea-industry-in-india</id>
    <published>2022-03-21T02:40:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:05:47-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/new-trends-defining-the-tea-industry-in-india"/>
    <title>New trends defining the tea industry in India</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="mb-4">The demand for premium teas has increased and customers are displaying an active interest in the purchase of premium teas online which, in turn, is facilitating sales by providing additional product information and bolstering consumer knowledge and awareness.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/new-trends-defining-the-tea-industry-in-india">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2 mt-4">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center">
<div class="col-md-1"><img class="img-fluid" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/IR-Logo.png?v=1647843936"></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="https://www.indiaretailing.com/2022/02/21/retail/new-trends-defining-the-tea-industry-in-india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">The Organic Magazine</a>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 mt-3">The demand for premium teas has increased and customers are displaying an active interest in the purchase of <a href="/collections/all" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">premium teas online</a> which, in turn, is facilitating sales by providing additional product information and bolstering consumer knowledge and awareness.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Tea is one of the most loved beverages in India and across the world. People have enjoyed tea since times immemorial and consider it to be one of the most cherished parts of their native culture. The love of Indian audiences for this super beverage has given the tea industry a loyal customer base in the country, which has resulted in fast-paced growth in recent times.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">In the past few decades, tea has become a multi-million dollar industry and India is the second-largest producer of tea globally, after China. According to expertmarketresearch.com, the Indian tea industry is expected to grow at a CAGR of about 4.2% in the 2021-26 period and reach an approximate volume of 1.40 million tonnes by the end of this period.</p>
<h4 class="mt-5 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Some trends that are dictating the landscape of the tea industry in India are as follows:</h4>
<h4 class="mt-0 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">The emergence of tea as a wellness superfood</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Due to the ongoing Covid pandemic, there is a huge resurgence of <a href="/blogs/all/boost-your-immunity-system-tips" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">teas with proven health benefits</a>. It has established itself as a wellness and lifestyle beverage and several new varieties and blends of tea are emerging in the market. <a href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Immunity-boosting teas</a> and superfoods with Ayurvedic ingredients like Turmeric, Ashwagandha, Moringa, Tulsi, etc., are in big demand.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">The Indian government’s role in inviting key players to invest in the wellness sector under its flagship “Make in India” scheme and its move to establish the Ministry of AYUSH is also indicative of the thriving health and wellness market in the country. As per a study by Numr Research, about 443 million Indian millennials spend more than Rs. 4000 on their health and wellness every month. Both established companies and startups have caught on to this trend and have witnessed phenomenal growth.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">One can say that the viral outbreak has transformed people’s preferences forever and that the increased concern for health will translate into higher purchases of healthy foods and beverages in the foreseeable future.</p>
<a class="d-block mt-4 mb-5" href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2485/1434/files/clipboard-image_23.png?v=1608206031" alt="Immunity Booster Teas" class="text-center mx-auto"> </a>
<h4 class="mt-0 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">Increasing customer preference for premium teas</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">With the advent of globalization and internet penetration, there has been a substantial surge in consumer demand, which has sparked new trends in the tea segment. As the variety of teas available to customers increased due to the opening of global barriers and the advent of e-commerce, discerning customers started seeking innovation and diversity in the products being offered by tea brands.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">In this scenario, the demand for <a href="/collections/gifts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">premium teas</a> has increased. As customers are displaying an active interest in the purchase of premium teas online, this medium is facilitating sales by providing additional product information and bolstering consumer knowledge and awareness. These premium teas include <a href="/collections/chai" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">immunity-boosting specialty</a> and <a href="/collections/flavoured-teas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">flavored teas</a>, and the younger generation is lapping them up.</p>
<a class="d-block mt-4 mb-5" href="/blogs/all/indias-7-most-expensive-teas-would-you-buy-one"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/valuable-teas-banner.jpg?v=1614382217" alt="Most Expensive Teas" class="text-center mx-auto"> </a>
<h4 class="mt-0 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">Eco-friendly and sustainable packaging</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Tea packaging has come a long way over the years. Standup pouches have become the preferred choice for many of today’s top brands in the beverage market because they are able to hold a large amount of the product, and more of these can fit on shelves at retail stores. Stand-up pouches for tea packaging keep the leaves fresh and protect against outside elements that can compromise the flavor, aroma, and healthful benefits of the product. We, at Golden Tips, are also using zipper pouch bags because they help maintain longer shelf life for the natural leaves that haven’t been treated with harmful chemicals to preserve their longevity.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">These tea pouches are recyclable, landfill friendly, and don’t rip, tear, or break like traditional boxes or cartons. They can keep both loose-leaf and individually packaged tea protected. The wide face of stand-up pouches acts as the perfect surface for your company’s branding and designs that reflect its sustainable values and practices. This trend has only accelerated with the Covid pandemic and tea brands are rolling out biodegradable tea bags, muslin tea bags, improved packaging in paper tins, and removing plastics from outer packaging.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">In this scenario, the demand for premium teas has increased. As customers are displaying an active interest in the purchase of premium teas online, this medium is facilitating sales by providing additional product information and bolstering consumer knowledge and awareness. These premium teas include immunity-boosting specialty and flavored teas, and the younger generation is lapping them up.</p>
<h4 class="mt-5 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">Growing brand consciousness</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">As gifting tea packages at corporate events, weddings, etc., becomes a common trend, brand consciousness comes into play. People are now progressively opting for branded labels instead of products from the unorganized sector. This has led to increased global investment in tea brands that have a compelling story to tell and a scalable business model.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">As per Neilsen’s insights, Indian consumers these days look at food labels more than ever before and are willing to pay more for products that make the cut, especially those with added nutrients. They are also more loyal to trusted brands. The surge in brand preference has also come because of the inclination towards health and hygiene factors since people generally expect a product to be premium &amp; reliable if it is branded. Customers who are concerned about the authenticity and hygiene of the product are also likely to turn towards reputed brands. Customers today are looking for innovation, flexibility, and compatibility for their fast-paced lifestyle. The variety and reach of a brand can provide all of these under one umbrella. Conclusively, branding and labels will be on the rise in the future.</p>
<h4 class="mt-5 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">Use of new-age technology in tea production and marketing</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Working from home with limited social activities and several other pandemic-induced restrictions have pushed businesses to adopt the digital format for survival. And when it comes to the tea industry specifically, the landscape appears to be no different. Not surprisingly, the advent of technology in the tea industry is proving to be a game-changer. One of the ways in which technology helps to ease the process in the tea industry is by digitizing tea farming to consolidate financially, and field-level records of the complete plantation activity, and supply chain management.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Technologies such as AI (Artificial Intelligence), improve quality as well as enable efficiency in the production stage. The use of technology makes the processes more precise and accurate, and this reduces the probability of mistakes and wastages. The infusion of technology in the manufacturing process reduces the cost of production and time consumption of the entire activity significantly. Needless to mention, as operations become more efficient, the chances of human error shrinks and the amount of time spent on unnecessary tasks reduces, and the organization saves expenditure and generates more revenue.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">With the ever-changing times, tea companies have also shifted their approach to targeting customers. They are using less of the traditional marketing strategies, such as television, papers, and billboards, and have since embraced the digital space. Although not all traditional marketing techniques have ended, digital marketing is far more favored. It provides several opportunities to brands, regardless of their size, to give real-time and personalized customers experience and garner increased AOV (Average Order Values). Greater visibility via digital marketing will also attract more overseas customers who are enthusiastic about purchasing tea from India, owing to their unmatched quality. This will further help Indian brands to enhance their economies of scale.</p>
<h4 class="mt-5 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">Increased tea consumption during Covid times</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">There is a clear increase in the consumption of tea after the pandemic outbreak and the numbers prove it out. During FY20-21, India consumed 89.24% of its tea production, as per the latest data available with the Tea Board India. According to the Tea Board, India’s consumption rose to 1,145 million kg in 2020-21 from 1,116 million Kg in the previous fiscal. This shows a Y-o-Y increase of 2.60%.</p>
<h4 class="mt-5 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">E-commerce and D2C brands fuelling the growth of the tea industry</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Last year, offline stores remained shut during the lockdown except for the ones dealing in essential items. This resulted in e-commerce growing at a phenomenal pace in India with order volume increasing by 36% (Source: The Hindu) in the last quarter of 2020. From personal care to food and beverage, consumers took to buying everything online. However, as the market opened up in 2021, it didn’t take long for customers to venture into a brick-and-mortar mode of shopping.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">The pandemic also saw the rise of many D2C (direct-to-consumer) tea brands in India, witnessing phenomenal growth by having an ‘online-only’ sales strategy. But, entrepreneurs believe that experiential shopping will never go out of fashion, and these D2C brands are now gearing up to foray into physical retail. Even traditional brands are aiming to expand their offline presence.</p>
<h4 class="mt-5 mb-2 fs-24 font-bold mb-3">Mushrooming of Tea Boutiques and Cafes</h4>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Tea stalls are a common sight across India but they are typically fragmented and unorganized. Tea café chains emerging across India are giving consumers a midway option between at-home consumption and the humble roadside stall. A number of companies with tea outlets similar to modern coffee chains have mushroomed, and are slowly revolutionizing the tea industry in India. These companies are looking to appeal to young Indians by offering them an upgraded version of the tea at “Dhabas” and their efforts are paying off. Some of these start-ups are now national chains.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">To conclude, companies with tea outlets are opening their own tea café chains revolutionizing the tea industry. Tea companies are now banking on innovation and the use of new marketing techniques to spur higher consumption, which has already been seeing an increase since the outbreak of the pandemic.</p>
<a class="d-block mt-4 mb-5" href="/blogs/all/golden-tips-opens-its-flagship-tea-boutique-and-cafe-teattoria"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/MicrosoftTeams-image_18.png?v=1645617612" alt="Flagship Tea Boutique and Cafe Teattoria" class="text-center mx-auto"> </a>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/why-shouldn-t-darjeeling-be-everyone-s-cup-of-tea</id>
    <published>2022-03-09T04:01:54-06:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:05:39-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/why-shouldn-t-darjeeling-be-everyone-s-cup-of-tea"/>
    <title>Why shouldn’t Darjeeling be everyone’s cup of tea?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="mb-4">Some people travel for leisure, many people travel for food and some travel for both. So, it would be fair to say that there would be people who travel for the drink that many of us just can’t do without, first thing in the morning.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/why-shouldn-t-darjeeling-be-everyone-s-cup-of-tea">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center mt-4">
<div class="col-md-2" style="background: #00000059; padding: 10px 5px 0;"><img class="img-fluid" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/et-hospitality.png?v=1646816870" width=""></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="https://hospitality.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/speaking-heads/why-shouldnt-darjeeling-be-everyones-cup-of-tea/89399730" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">The Organic Magazine</a>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 mt-3">With the government allowing tea garden owners to use a part of their unused land for the purpose of tea tourism, there is also a growing need to educate tea estate owners, guides, and travel agencies on the benefits of tea tourism.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Some people travel for leisure, many people travel for food and some travel for both. So, it would be fair to say that there would be people who travel for the drink that many of us just can’t do without, first thing in the morning. There are few better places to savour a cup of tea than at a tea plantation, close to the land where the leaves were plucked from, overlooking verdant hillsides and picturesque valleys. India has a plethora of stays for tea lovers, mostly estates from yesteryears which have been refurbished into quaint homestays.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">In the British era, <a href="/collections/darjeeling" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Darjeeling</a> was one of the favourite retreats for the officers. With its quaint colonial charm and endless green stretches of lush tea plantations, the region has been a favourite for people who have yearned to do away with city life for some time, and get lost in magical natural beauty. Nowadays, estates have started adding varied experiences like horse riding, nature trains, visit to local families, cultural evenings, among other things. Hence, Tea tourism provides travellers with the opportunity to interact with nature, wild-life and simultaneously extract the goodness of socio-cultural diversity of the region.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">People can learn about local cultures by getting a first-hand account of the rituals and ceremonies. Boosting rural tourism will help solve socio-economic problems and alleviate the livelihoods of denizens.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">It would not be incorrect to state that tea tourism can alter the tea-drinking experience entirely by helping us understand the origins, processing, and terroir of tea in an intellectual manner. It can engage sensorially - we can touch the dew laden tea leaves and smell the earthiness of the soil in which it grows. Sometimes to taste the best tea, you just need to have a sense of adventure.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">With the government allowing tea garden owners to use a part of their unused land for the purpose of tea tourism, there is also a growing need to educate tea estate owners, guides, and travel agencies on the benefits of tea tourism.</p>
<h4 class="mt-5 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Choice of Darjeeling Teas</h4>
<div class="row mb-5">
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20">
<a class="text-center" href="/collections/all/products/golden-orange-pekoe-tea-tin-can"> <img class="mb-3" style="filter: drop-shadow(0 10px 10px #0400004d);" alt="Herbyoga" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Golden-Orange-Pekoe-Tea---Tin-Can.png?v=1639139613"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Golden Orange Pekoe Tea - Tin Can</p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="/collections/all/products/golden-orange-pekoe-tea-tin-can"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20">
<a class="text-center" href="/collections/darjeeling/products/pure-green-tea-royal-brocade-cloth-bag-1?variant=30929166401629"> <img class="mb-3" style="filter: drop-shadow(0 10px 10px #0400004d);" alt="Herbyoga" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Pure_Green_Tea_-_Royal_Brocade_Cloth_Bag_c485a31d-32df-4ed7-b358-797313177624.png?v=1625300246"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Pure Green Tea - Royal Brocade Cloth Bag</p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="/collections/darjeeling/products/pure-green-tea-royal-brocade-cloth-bag-1?variant=30929166401629"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20">
<a class="text-center" href="/collections/darjeeling/products/darjeeling-tea-tin-can-100gm"> <img class="mb-3" style="filter: drop-shadow(0 10px 10px #0400004d);" alt="Herbyoga" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Darjeeling-Tea---Tin-Can.png?v=1616672698"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Darjeeling Tea - Tin Can <br><br></p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="/collections/darjeeling/products/darjeeling-tea-tin-can-100gm"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">The Challenges</h2>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Tea tourism in India is still in its nascent stage. Given our colonial history and our own rich legacy, India has immense potential to offer a robust tea-tasting and tourism experience. However, it lacks proper structure, policy and marketing initiatives.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Detailed planning is required for making tea tourism more attractive in India. The Tea Board and the Tourism Ministry at the Centre can join hands to play a crucial role in this endeavor. Tea companies too should come forward and aim to promote Eco-Tourism by devoting land which is not feasible for plantation tea for multifarious tea-related activities and setting up resorts and homestays.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">This will boost the economy of the region by creating new jobs, increasing revenues of all stakeholders, improving infrastructure and planting a sense of cultural exchange between visitors and locals.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Organizing tea festivals in the tea gardens, <a href="/pages/showrooms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">visits to tea boutiques</a> located in nearby towns where exotic teas, tea wares &amp; souvenirs are on display, will further drive interest in such tea tourism.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Tea gastronomy could be highlighted with the promotion of tea-infused drinks and beverages, confectionery, food and this could further add to the many lucrative avenues for the areas around the tea estate. These steps could help promote, upgrade &amp; highlight the consumption of teas as well as their <a href="/blogs/all/7-health-benefits-darjeeling-tea" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">multi-health benefits</a>, which fall within the ambit of Tea Tourism. Most of the above measures can inject a much-needed impetus to the Tea Tourism industry, tea trade in general, rural areas scattered around tea plantations, tourist guides &amp; interpreters, manufacturers &amp; dealers of <a href="/blogs/all/3-must-have-tea-accessories" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tea accessories</a>, etc. However, there needs to be a concerted effort involving all stakeholders to move ahead in this direction.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Lastly, the pandemic has led people to search for more isolated and secluded spots, which has slowly resulted in more and more people being interested in these beautifully preserved estates. This accounts for the rise in Indian tourists visiting tea estates, which were predominantly popular with foreigners. This momentum needs not only to be preserved but also to be accelerated further.</p>
</div>
    <div class="bg-light-green d-block img-150 align-items-center row-styling mt-4 mb-45">
        <h4 class="mb-0 mt-0 fs-24 font-bold" style="padding-left: 20px;">Suggested Readings:</h4>
        <ul>
        <li><a style="border-bottom: none;" href="/blogs/all/how-to-buy-authentic-high-quality-darjeeling-tea" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">HOW TO BUY AUTHENTIC HIGH-QUALITY DARJEELING TEA </a></li>
        <li><a style="border-bottom: none;" href="/blogs/all/why-golden-tips-darjeeling-tea-is-best" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">WHY GOLDEN TIPS DARJEELING TEA IS BEST  </a></li>
        <li><a style="border-bottom: none;" href="/blogs/all/7-health-benefits-darjeeling-tea" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">7 HEALTH BENEFITS OF DARJEELING TEA</a></li>
        <li><a style="border-bottom: none;" href="/blogs/all/how-to-make-the-perfect-cup-of-darjeeling-tea" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">WHY SHOULDN’T DARJEELING BE EVERYONE’S CUP OF TEA?</a></li>
        <li><a style="border-bottom: none;" href="/blogs/all/all-you-need-to-know-about-darjeeling-first-flush-tea" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW ABOUT DARJEELING FIRST FLUSH TEA</a></li>
        <li><a style="border-bottom: none;" href="/blogs/all/discover-darjeeling-tea" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">DISCOVER YOURSELF WITH DARJEELING TEA</a></li>
        <li><a style="border-bottom: none;" href="/blogs/all/best-darjeeling-teas-with-milk?_pos=2&amp;_sid=7bd3b9c5f&amp;_ss=r" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">BEST DARJEELING TEAS WITH MILK</a></li>
        <li><a style="border-bottom: none;" href="/blogs/all/why-darjeeling-tea-is-called-the-champagne-of-teas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Why Darjeeling Tea Is Called the Champagne of Teas  </a></li>
        </ul>
        </div>    
<a class="d-block mt-5" href="/collections/darjeeling"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/yes-mobile_1800x_c3c5919a-0d60-48dc-8928-aa8905f5407b.jpg?v=1633082296" alt="Darjeeling Tea" class="text-center mx-auto lg-d-hide"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/say_yes_to_darjeeling.jpg?v=1633082296%5C" alt="Darjeeling Teas" class="text-center mx-auto sm-d-hide"> </a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/golden-tips-opens-its-flagship-tea-boutique-and-cafe-teattoria</id>
    <published>2022-02-23T06:02:49-06:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-01T06:53:08-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/golden-tips-opens-its-flagship-tea-boutique-and-cafe-teattoria"/>
    <title>Golden Tips&apos; opens its flagship tea boutique and café - Teattoria</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="mb-4">
Capturing the essence of Darjeeling is a home-grown tea brand 'Golden Tips Teas', which comes with a heritage of 80+ years and four generations of tea entrepreneurship. 
</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/golden-tips-opens-its-flagship-tea-boutique-and-cafe-teattoria">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center mt-4">
<div class="col-md-2 "><img class="img-fluid" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Millennium_post.jpg?v=1645527850" width=""></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold fs-22">First published on <a href="http://www.millenniumpost.in/entertainment/golden-tips-opens-its-flagship-tea-boutique-and-caf-teattoria-466362" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Millennium post </a>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">Capturing the essence of <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/darjeeling" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Darjeeling</a> is a home-grown tea brand 'Golden Tips Teas', which comes with a heritage of 80+ years and four generations of tea entrepreneurship. Following the 'direct from plantation + auction model', the expertise of 'Golden Tips' lies in sourcing, packaging and marketing of premium quality single-origin teas and tea blends. Apart from the domestic market, the company exports teas to 90+ countries with Russia, Japan, Mongolia, Nepal, Bhutan and now China being their main international markets.</p>
<div class="text-center mb-5 mt-5"><iframe style="box-shadow: 6px 6px 10px #7e7d7d75; border-radius: 15px;" title="YouTube video player" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SPeiKZQuArg?rel=0" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0"></iframe></div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">'Golden Tips' has recently opened its flagship <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/pages/showrooms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tea boutique</a> and cafe 'Teattoria' in Darjeeling. It offers Italian/ Continental and Oriental cuisine along with specialty teas and exotic mocktails.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 ">"We have endeavoured to cater to domestic as well as foreign customers, especially those visiting India, through our omnichannel presence across India and of course through our online route. Our specialised tea stores, including our flagship tea boutique and café 'Teattoria' are spread across Darjeeling, Kalimpong, Gangtok and are playing a major role in popularising the <a href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">finest teas of India</a> and making them available to connoisseurs," said the managing director of 'Golden Tips'.</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-0">Choices of Darjeeling Teas</h2>
<div class="row mb-5">
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20 mt-3">
<a class="text-center" href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/darjeeling/products/pure-green-tea-royal-brocade-cloth-bag-1"> <img class="mt-0" alt="Herbyoga" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/products/Untitled-2_4aecf968-f0f7-427d-9eb4-aa282dd14de4_480x.jpg?v=1637676658"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Pure Green Tea - Royal Brocade Cloth Bag</p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/darjeeling/products/pure-green-tea-royal-brocade-cloth-bag-1"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20 mt-3">
<a class="text-center" href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/darjeeling/products/darjeeling-tea-tin-can-100gm"> <img class="mt-0" alt="Herbyoga" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/products/Darjeeling-Tea-Tin-Can-_100gm_40a20530-39a1-4c66-a7c1-c42dc9f78bc4_480x.jpg?v=1637675984"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Darjeeling Tea - Tin Can</p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/darjeeling/products/darjeeling-tea-tin-can-100gm"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="col-md-4 p-relative">
<div class="product-desc-price text-center px-20 mt-3">
<a class="text-center" href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/darjeeling/products/pure-darjeeling-tea-royal-brocade-cloth-bag"> <img class="mt-0" alt="Herbyoga" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/products/Pure-Darjeeling-Tea---Royal-Brocade-Cloth-Bag_35e032f0-d3cf-4ef1-8ffc-a7d68fcd69af_480x.jpg?v=1613217262"> </a>
<p class="font-bold custom-text mt-2 mb-10">Pure Darjeeling Tea - Royal Brocade Cloth Bag</p>
<a class="text-center text-link" href="https://www.goldentipstea.in/collections/darjeeling/products/pure-darjeeling-tea-royal-brocade-cloth-bag"> <span class="btn-view-price">View Price</span> </a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-0">Some Pictures of café - Teattoria</h2>
<div class="row mt-4 d-flex-wrap d-flex">
    <div class="col-md-4 mb-3"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/teattoria/"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Teattori.png?v=1645611413" alt="" class="img-fluid"> </a>
</div>
    <div class="col-md-4 mb-3"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/teattoria/"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Teattoria-1.jpg?v=1645611021" alt="" class="img-fluid"> </a>
</div>
    <div class="col-md-4 mb-3"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/teattoria/">  <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Teattoria-2.jpg?v=1645611066" alt="" class="img-fluid"></a>
</div>
    <div class="col-md-4 mb-3"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/teattoria/"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Teattoria-3.jpg?v=1645611021" alt="" class="img-fluid"></a>
</div>
    <div class="col-md-4 mb-3"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/teattoria/"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Teattori-5.jpg?v=1645611021" alt="" class="img-fluid"></a>
</div>
    <div class="col-md-4 mb-3"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/teattoria/"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Teattoria-4.jpg?v=1645611021" alt="" class="img-fluid"></a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<a href="https://www.instagram.com/teattoria/" style="border-radius: 50px;background: linear-gradient(45deg, #f09433 0%,#e6683c 25%,#dc2743 50%,#cc2366 75%,#bc1888 100%) !important;text-decoration: none;padding: 15px 30px !important;margin-right: auto;margin-left: auto;display: block;max-width: 250px;width: 100%;color: white;font-size: 18px;" class="btn mx-auto">Follow Us on Instagram</a>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/madhav-sarda-the-magic-of-darjeeling-s-golden-tips</id>
    <published>2022-02-17T07:12:08-06:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:04:53-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/madhav-sarda-the-magic-of-darjeeling-s-golden-tips"/>
    <title>Madhav Sarda: The magic of Darjeeling‘s Golden Tips</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="" mb-4="">Tea. The love for this elixir made the British do some industrial reconnaissance and bring the seeds of Camellia Sinensis to the foothills of the mighty Himalayas, to Darjeeling. Darjeeling is blessed with a unique terroir with an altitude ranging between 1200 – 6000 ft above sea level.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/madhav-sarda-the-magic-of-darjeeling-s-golden-tips">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2">
<div class="row d-lg-flex align-items-center mt-4">
<div class="col-md-2 "><img class="img-fluid" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/The-organic-logo-CMYK.png?v=1645190529" width=""></div>
<div class="col-md-10">
<p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold  fs-22">First published on <a href="https://theorganicmagazine.com/meet-the-plantpreneur/madhav-sarda-the-magic-of-darjeelings-golden-tips/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">The Organic Magazine</a>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold">Tea, the love for this elixir made the British do some industrial reconnaissance and bring the seeds of Camellia Sinensis to the foothills of the mighty Himalayas, to Darjeeling. Darjeeling is blessed with a unique terroir with an altitude ranging between 1200 – 6000 ft above sea level. The steep slopes, ample humidity, rainfall, shade, moisture, and acidic soils infuse “magic” into the teas of this region. There is a certain air about the region and not surprisingly, Darjeeling teas are one of the most loved beverages around the globe with absolute uniqueness in flavor and aroma.</p>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-md-6">
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Capturing this very essence of Darjeeling is a tea brand that comes with a heritage of 80+ years and 4 generations of tea entrepreneurs – Golden Tips. Reminiscing about the history, Madhav Sarda, Managing Director, Golden Tips says, “When we started a few decades ago way back in 1933, the almost complete absence of a premium homegrown brand that could package and present the finest Darjeeling Teas to customers spurred us to start Golden Tips.”</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-6">
<div class="text-center"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/finest_teas.jpg?v=1645080850" alt="Finest Teas" class="img-fluid" srcset="" style="max-width: 416px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 mt-3">Today, Golden Tips follows the “Direct from Plantation + Auction model) and the brand’s expertise lies in sourcing, packaging and marketing of premium quality single origin teas, and tea blends. Apart from the domestic market, Golden Tips sells online to 90+ countries with Russia, Japan, Mongolia, Nepal, Bhutan and now China, the main international markets for B2B sales of the Golden Tips branded range.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Sarda adds, “Our endeavor has been to cater to domestic as well as foreign customers, especially those visiting India, through our omnichannel presence across India and of course through our website and marketplaces like Amazon. Our specialized and unique <a href="/pages/showrooms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tea Boutiques</a> spread across Darjeeling, Sikkim, etc are also a must-visit for tourists and play a major role in popularising the finest teas and making them available to connoisseurs.”</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">The nuances of fine teas</h2>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-md-6">
<p class="custom-text mb-10">As in every business, the initial years were the most challenging. General ignorance of the trade, lack of awareness of the nuances of fine teas among the general public, and its consequences on the possible customer base were just some of the teething issues, informs Madhav. “Also, most retail chains were either reluctant to keep our products, or if agreeable, they were ready to keep just a few variants in small quantities. This made little business sense as the impact would be minimal in terms of visibility and awareness,” he adds.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-6">
<div class="text-center"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/The_nuances_of_fine_teas.jpg?v=1645080850" alt="Finest Teas" class="img-fluid" srcset=""></div>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 mt-3">Golden Tips has a vast and eclectic range of the finest <a class="text-link" href="/collections/darjeeling" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Darjeeling</a>, <a class="text-link" href="/collections/sikkim" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sikkim</a>, <a class="text-link" href="/collections/assam" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Assam</a>, <a class="text-link" href="/collections/nilgiri" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nilgiris</a>, and other Indian teas sourced from the best plantations across the country. These teas are packaged in varied styles and packs. Like Economy packs, Handcrafted Gift packs consisting of <a class="text-link" href="/collections/wooden-jute-boxes" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">hand-carved wooden boxes</a>, <a class="text-link" href="/collections/brocade-bags" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fancy Brocade</a> and Velvet cloth bags, Jute boxes, etc. The brand also manufactures commercial packs in paper cartons and tin cans, as also gift packaging and assortments.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Madhav, who is also an experienced tea taster, shares, “Many of the offerings that we have are Organic like our 2nd Flush Ruby Regalia Black Tea from the famous Arya Tea Estate, Organic Moonlight White Tea etc., amongst a host of other exotic teas. However, presently, we are not using the Certified Organic tag, though Golden Tips is certified by IMO India (IMO India is an independent certification body for Organic Agriculture that has been carrying out audits and certification since 1995) and is also JAS (Japanese Agriculture Standard) Certified which ensures we comply with JAS Standards established by the Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries, Japan. We plan to launch our initial Certified Organic variants this year.”</p>
<h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Sustainable sourcing</h2>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-md-6">
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Is a magical land of ingredients. All of these products have strong wellness connotations that have been accepted by people globally. India grows about 25 % of the world’s tea in addition to exotic herbs, spices, and superfoods, like Turmeric, Moringa, Ashwagandha, Tulsi, and Giloy.</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Madhav points out, “Our teas are freshly sourced from the picturesque tea gardens of Darjeeling, Assam, Kangra, Sikkim, and Nilgiris. So, our ingredients (Teas and Spices) are all sourced from within the country, with some being sourced sustainably too.”</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-6">
<div class="text-center"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Sustainable_sourcing.jpg?v=1645080850" alt="Finest Teas" class="img-fluid" srcset=""></div>
</div>
</div>
<p class="custom-text mb-10 mt-3">Darjeeling Tea received the GI tag in 2004. This tag ensures that tea grown just in the district of Darjeeling can be sold as Darjeeling. Besides, none other than those registered as authorized users by the Tea Board are allowed to use the popular product name. Madhav observes, “The acquisition of this Tag has had a positive fall-out in the region as it fetches a slightly premium price for the plantation owners, and hence a ripple effect percolates down to the tea workers even though a lot more needs to be done by the Government. Darjeeling Tea has been able to maintain an even curve when the tea sector at large has gone through a low phase owing to strikes and climate change. It has also brought about the consolidation of ownership and new investments in the tea industry of the region.”</p>
<p class="custom-text mb-10">Elucidating on the future roadmap for Golden Tips, Madhav says, “We have recently opened our flagship Tea Café and restaurant “Teattoria” in Darjeeling. It offers Italian/ Continental and Oriental cuisine along with our Specialty Teas. We now plan to expand our footprint through our offline/ physical retail operations across Metro and Tier 2 cities in India by opening niche experiential tea boutiques and stores. We are exploring this route and hopefully shall finalize some tie-ups after the current wave of the pandemic subsides. We also intend to give a thrust to our online operations to capture a larger market in the near future.”</p>
</div>
<a class="d-block mt-5" href="/collections/darjeeling"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/yes-mobile_1800x_c3c5919a-0d60-48dc-8928-aa8905f5407b.jpg?v=1633082296" alt="Darjeeling Tea" class="text-center mx-auto lg-d-hide"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/say_yes_to_darjeeling.jpg?v=1633082296%5C" alt="Darjeeling Teas" class="text-center mx-auto sm-d-hide"> </a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/raise-a-toast-to-tea</id>
    <published>2022-02-15T00:22:50-06:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-02T03:05:50-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/raise-a-toast-to-tea"/>
    <title>Raise a toast to tea</title>
    <author>
      <name>Golden Tips Tea</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="mb-2">Tea is one of the most loved beverages in India and across the world. People have enjoyed tea since time immemorial and consider it to be one of the most cherished parts of their native culture. Indians’ love for this super beverage has given the tea industry a loyal customer base in the country, which has resulted in fast-paced growth.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.goldentipstea.com/blogs/news/raise-a-toast-to-tea">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="custom-container px-2 mt-4">
    <p style="font-style: italic;" class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold  fs-22 mt-4">First published on <a href="https://www.dailypioneer.com/2022/vivacity/raise-a-toast-to-tea.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Daily Pioneer</a>; contributed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhav-sarda-6600232/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-link">Madhav Sarda</a>, Managing Director, Golden Tips Tea</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10 fon-bold">Tea is one of the most loved beverages in India and across the world. People have enjoyed tea since time immemorial and consider it to be one of the most cherished parts of their native culture. Indians’ love for this super beverage has given the tea industry a loyal customer base in the country, which has resulted in fast-paced growth.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">According to expertmarketresearch.com, the Indian tea industry is expected to grow at a CAGR of about 4.2 percent in the 2021-26 period and reach an approximate valuation of 1.40 million tonnes by the end of this period.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10 font-bold"><strong> Some of the trends that are dictating the landscape of the tea industry in India are as follows:</strong></p>
    <h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Tea as a wellness superfood</h2>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">Due to the ongoing Covid pandemic situation, there is a huge resurgence of teas with proven health benefits. <a href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas" target="_blank">Immunity boosting teas</a> and superfoods with Ayurvedic ingredients like turmeric, ashwagandha, moringa, tulsi, etc are in big demand.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">As per a study by Numr Research, about 443 million Indian millennials spend more than `4,000 on their health and wellness every month. Both established companies and start-ups have caught on to this trend and have witnessed phenomenal growth.</p>
    <div class="bg-light-green row sm-d-block img-150 align-items-center row-styling mt-5 mb-45">
    <div class="col-md-9">
    <h4 class="font-bold fs-20">Herbyoga - Immunity Booster Desi Kadha Tea</h4>
    <p class="custom-text mb-1">Herbyoga Immunity Booster Desi Kadha Tea is made with selected ingredients like Ashwagandha, Tulsi, Giloy, and many more Indian herbs which help in boosting immunity to the next level. Every way of natural care is a wonder Cure!</p>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-3 text-center mb-2">
    <a class="text-decoration-none" href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas/products/herbyoga-desi-kadha-herbal-tea-immunity-booster-kadha-tea"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Herbyoga_-_Immunity_Booster_Desi_Kadha_Tea.png?v=1622711645" alt="Herbyoga" class="img-fluid mb-3"></a>
    <div class="view-all mt-2 mb-4"><a class="seeallbutton text-link" target="_blank" href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas/products/herbyoga-desi-kadha-herbal-tea-immunity-booster-kadha-tea">View Price</a></div>
    </div>
    </div>
    <div class="bg-light-green row sm-d-block img-150 align-items-center row-styling mt-5 mb-45">
    <div class="col-md-9">
    <h4 class="font-bold fs-20">Earl Grey Tea - Tin Can</h4>
    <p class="custom-text mb-1">Earl Grey, the most popular tea blend in the world is named after the British Minister, the 2nd Earl Grey. Our Earl Grey Indian Tea is an interesting take on this classic combination of the finest black tea leaves scented with natural oil from the ripened peel of the bergamot fruit, a pear shaped sour orange originally found in southern Italy.</p>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-3 text-center mb-2">
    <a class="text-decoration-none" href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas/products/darjeeling-earl-grey-tea-tin-can-100gm"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/Earl_Grey_Tea_-_Tin_Can.png?v=1625300245" alt="Herbyoga" class="img-fluid mb-3"></a>
    <div class="view-all mt-2 mb-4"><a class="seeallbutton text-link" target="_blank" href="/collections/immunity-booster-teas/products/darjeeling-earl-grey-tea-tin-can-100gm">View Price</a></div>
    </div>
    </div>
    <h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Increasing customer preference for premium teas</h2>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">With the advent of globalisation and increased internet penetration, there has been a substantial surge in the complexities of consumer demand. As the variety of teas available increased due to the removal of global barriers and the advent of e-commerce, discerning customers started seeking innovation and diversity in products being offered by tea brands.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">In this scenario, the demand for premium teas has increased. These premium teas include immunity-boosting, speciality and <a href="/collections/flavoured-teas" target="_blank">flavoured teas</a>. The younger generation is lapping these up.</p>
    <h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Eco-friendly and sustainable packaging</h2>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">Tea packaging has come a long way over the years. Stand up pouches have become the preferred choice for many of today's top brands in the beverage market. Stand-up pouches for tea packaging keep the leaves fresh and protect against outside elements. Zipper pouch bags help maintain a longer shelf life of the natural leaves.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">These tea pouches are recyclable, landfill friendly, and don't rip, tear, or break like traditional boxes or cartons. The wide face of stand-up pouches acts as the perfect surface for your company's branding and designs.</p>
    <h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Growing brand consciousness</h2>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">As gifting tea packages at corporate events and festivals has become a trend, brand consciousness comes into play. People are now progressively opting for branded labels instead of products from the unorganised sector. This has led to increased global investment in tea brands that have a compelling story to tell and with a scalable business model.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">As per Nielsen's insights, Indian consumers these days look at food labels more than ever before and are willing to pay more for products that make the cut, especially those with added nutrients. They are also more loyal to trusted brands.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">The surge in brand preference has also come because of the inclination towards health and hygiene factors. Since people generally expect a product to be premium and reliable if it is branded.</p>
    <h2 class="mt-30 mb-2 fs-34 font-bold mb-3">Mushrooming of <a href="/pages/showrooms" target="_blank">tea boutiques and cafes</a>
    </h2>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">Tea stalls are a common sight across India, but they are typically fragmented and unorganised. Tea café chains emerging across India are giving consumers a midway option between at-home consumption and the humble roadside stall. A number of companies with tea outlets similar to modern coffee chains have mushroomed, and are slowly revolutionising the tea industry in India. These companies are looking to appeal to young Indians by offering them an upgraded version of the tea dhabas and their efforts are paying off. Some of these start-ups are now national chains.</p>
    <p class="custom-text mb-10">These tea chains are a much better alternative to the open-air tea vendors, offering consumers a more relaxed environment, with seating and snacks.</p>
    <!-- <div class="text-center mb-5 mt-5"><iframe style="box-shadow: 0 0 10px #80808047;" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SqtGVZ2O9N0?rel=0" title="YouTube video player" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0"></iframe></div> -->
    </div>
    <a class="d-block mt-5" href="/collections/darjeeling"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/yes-mobile_1800x_c3c5919a-0d60-48dc-8928-aa8905f5407b.jpg?v=1633082296" alt="Darjeeling Tea" class="text-center mx-auto lg-d-hide"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0291/9381/files/say_yes_to_darjeeling.jpg?v=1633082296%5C" alt="Darjeeling Teas" class="text-center mx-auto sm-d-hide"> </a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
